<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><!-- smartling.translate_paths = properties/entry --><!-- smartling.placeholder_format_custom = (mm/dd/yyyy)|(\[.+?\])|(\{.+?\})|(\d)|(%)|(-) --><properties><entry key="profile.fm.significance.p1">&lt;b&gt;Significance&lt;/b&gt; comes by way of approval or affection from significant others. It brings a desire for a career setting that has a positive effect on others. This usually comes about through cooperative efforts or association with a particular group of people.</entry><entry key="profile.fm.secondary.need">{0} &lt;b&gt;Secondary Fundamental Need&lt;/b&gt; is to achieve a sense of &lt;b&gt;{1}&lt;/b&gt; ({2}).</entry><entry key="profile.fm.security.p1">&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt; comes by way of acquisition of assets, position, education, or a sense of belonging. Those motivated by security are likely attracted to a career setting that provides for a stable future.</entry><entry key="profile.fm.primary.need">{0}''s &lt;b&gt;Primary Fundamental Need&lt;/b&gt; is to achieve a sense of &lt;b&gt;{1}&lt;/b&gt; ({2}).</entry><entry key="profile.fm.heading">FUNDAMENTAL&lt;br/&gt;NEEDS</entry><entry key="profile.fm.principles.p2">&lt;li&gt;A mismanaged Fundamental Need can become a destructive force in any area of life.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Setbacks may cause a temporary shift away from the Fundamental Need to the Secondary Need.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Identifying a Fundamental Need can increase the understanding of a person's attitudes, motivation, and behavior.&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.fm.significance.heading">SIGNIFICANCE</entry><entry key="profile.fm.principles.p1">&lt;li class="small-text"&gt;One of the three Fundamental Needs will be dominant throughout most of a person's life, but many people will identify a Secondary Need as well.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li class="small-text"&gt;Fundamental Needs have a significant impact on one's attitude, behavior, and motivation in the work context.&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.fm.learnmore">Learn more below</entry><entry key="profile.fm.security.heading">SECURITY</entry><entry key="profile.fm.principles.heading">Principles that apply to&lt;br /&gt;Fundamental Needs</entry><entry key="profile.fm.summary">There are three fundamental needs that everyone experiences in life. However, one will usually dominate and contribute significantly to a person's outlook, attitude, motivation, and behavior.</entry><entry key="profile.fm.control.heading">CONTROL</entry><entry key="profile.fm.control.p1">&lt;strong&gt;Control&lt;/strong&gt; manifests itself in efforts to influence or manage circumstances or people. It carries a longing for a setting that will allow the opportunity to control the work setting or have the power to manage people/events.</entry></properties>