<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><!-- smartling.translate_paths = properties/entry --><!-- smartling.placeholder_format_custom = (mm/dd/yyyy)|(\[.+?\])|(\{.+?\})|(\d)|(%)|(-) --><properties><entry key="&lt;li&gt;Having">to go step by step without knowing the outcome&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;People who are insensitive to the feelings of others&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Not getting a fair chance to explain oneself&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.learning.global.vs.analytical.p2">However, even though individuals find themselves in both categories, they gravitate toward just one style.</entry><entry key="profile.learning.global.vs.analytical.p1">Learning Style explains how the individual interacts with new information. There are two extremes: the &lt;b&gt;global&lt;/b&gt; learning style and the &lt;b&gt;analytical&lt;/b&gt; learning style. No person is bound by one learning style.</entry><entry key="profile.learning.global.characterstics.percentage">{0}% GLOBAL LEARNER CHARACTERISTICS</entry><entry key="profile.learning.global.frustration.p1">&lt;li&gt;Having to show the steps used to arrive at a particular answer&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Accepting criticism of others without taking it personally&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Not knowing the purpose for doing a particular task&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Not receiving enough credit for the efforts made&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Having to explain something analytically and in detail&lt;/li&gt;  </entry><entry key="profile.learning.global.vs.analytical">GLOBAL LEARNER vs. ANALYTICAL LEARNER</entry><entry key="profile.learning.analytical.heading">ANALYTICAL</entry><entry key="profile.learning.analytical.greater">An &lt;b&gt;analytical&lt;/b&gt; learner hears new information and tends to listen for specific details. Getting the overall concept that the details describe may be sometimes difficult for the &lt;b&gt;analytical&lt;/b&gt; learner. In following directions, the &lt;b&gt;Analyst&lt;/b&gt; listens for	details and may become particularly frustrated if instructions are repeated.</entry><entry key="profile.learning.global.heading">GLOBAL</entry><entry key="profile.learning.global.greater">A &lt;b&gt;global&lt;/b&gt; learner sees the big picture or overall view, while the analytical learner focuses on the parts that make up the big picture. &lt;b&gt;global&lt;/b&gt; learners hear new information by listening to the "gist" of what is being communicated, quickly getting the main idea or topic. Remembering the details may be somewhat difficult. In following directions the &lt;strong&gt;Global&lt;/strong&gt; learner listens for "what is supposed to be done", not necessarily "how to do it". </entry><entry key="profile.learning.analytical.p1">&lt;li&gt;Likes going step by step in a sequential order&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Typically self-motivated, logical and focused&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Must be prepared and needs to know what to expect&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Pays close attention to details and specifics&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Can find the facts but may miss the main idea&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Often values facts over intuition and feelings&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Remembers specifics and prefers organization&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Prefers to finish one thing at a time&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Has a sense of fairness&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;May prefer direct answers&lt;/li&gt; </entry><entry key="profile.learning.global.p1">&lt;li&gt;Learns by discussion and cooperates in group efforts&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Does several things at once and may skip steps/details&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Sees the big picture and relationships between ideas&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Reads between the lines and sees many options&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Works hard to please and tries to avoid conflict&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Goes with the flow and is generally flexible&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Tends to avoid individual competition&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Paraphrases in explaining a perspective&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.learning.heading">PRIMARY LEARNING STYLE</entry><entry key="profile.learning.global.frustration">GLOBAL LEARNER FRUSTRATIONS</entry><entry key="profile.learning.analytical.frustration">ANALYTICAL LEARNER FRUSTRATIONS</entry><entry key="profile.learning.analytical.frustration.p1">&lt;li&gt;Listening to a long explanation when all that is needed is a simple "yes" or "no" response&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Listening to an overview without knowing the steps involved&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Not understanding how an employer/instructor evaluates&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Not finishing one task before going on to the next&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Having opinions expressed as fact without evidence&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Not having an understanding of the purpose of the task&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Dealing with broad generalities and not having the specifics&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.learning.analytical.characterstics.percentage">{0}% ANALYTICAL LEARNER CHARACTERISTICS</entry></properties>