<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><!-- smartling.translate_paths = properties/entry --><!-- smartling.placeholder_format_custom = (mm/dd/yyyy)|(\[.+?\])|(\{.+?\})|(\d)|(%)|(-) --><properties><entry key="profile.motivation.power.compliance.equal">{0} does not have a strong preference in either direction. A preference may change with the context and/or relationships. In some situations {0} is more motivated by a capacity to manage people and circumstances well. In other situations {0} is more motivated and comfortable by just receiving clear instructions and direction to be followed.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.hygiene.accomplishment.equal">{0} does not have a strong preference in either direction. A preference may change with the context and/or relationships. In some situations {0} is more motivated by the challenge of achievement, recognition, advancement, and overcoming significant obstacles. In other situations {0} is more motivated by an attractive environment, job security, appropriate compensation, adequate supervision, and satisfactory work conditions.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.freedom.greater.text">{0} is motivated by the freedom and the latitude to make the decisions, adjustments and take action on matters deemed important. This individual is not necessarily as motivated by routines and will often invent new ways to avoid routine.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.consistency.greater.text">{0} is motivated by experiencing a consistency and/or familiarity of predictable routines. This individual is not necessarily as motivated by a strong need to have the freedom and the latitude to make decisions, adjustments and take action on matters deemed important.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.what">WHAT</entry><entry key="&amp;">managing others as well as working productively on a team or for a supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.headline">{0} {1}% &lt;br/&gt;vs. {2} {3}%</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.paragraph">&lt;p&gt;Understanding our motivations - how we are motivated, why we are motivated, and what motivates us - is critical for both</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.attainment.greater.text">{0} is motivated by the opportunity to pursue and achieve the valued goal or objective more than being recognized for the efforts made.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.taskcompletion.greater.text">{0} is more motivated by a clear definition and completion of the assigned (or chosen) task. There is a sense of satisfaction when the work is complete, but possibly a frustration when it is not. Process work may be experienced as boring and demotivating.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.activity.greater.text">{0} is motivated by "what" is being done more than "who" it may involve.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.why">WHY</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.affliation.greater.text">{0} is motivated by "who" is involved in a situation rather than "what" is being done.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.exchangeofideas.greater.text">{0} shows a preference and is motivated by the opportunity to explore as well as to dialogue on ideas, strategies, vision and challenges. {0} is not as motivated by receiving direction without giving input.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.power.greater.text">{0} is motivated by a capacity to manage people and circumstances well. This individual is more of an initiator than responder and is likely demotivated by being told what to do and how to do it.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.selfaffirmed.greater.text">{0} possesses an internal sense of adding value to the surrounding environment and does not necessarily need a significant amount of appreciation, encouragement and support of others to experience a sense of self-esteem.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.prefersprocess.greater.text">{0} is motivated by a preference to do the work well and stay with the process at hand. What is being done and how it is done are both important. Completing the task is not necessary to feel motivated or rewarded. Upon completion of a task or project this individual is usually ready to address the next process.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.how">HOW</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.compliance.greater.text">{0} is motivated and comfortable when given clear instructions and direction to be followed. There may be a discomfort with having to lead or make decisions for a group. This individual is more of a responder than an initiator.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.recongnitioneffort.attainment.equal">{0} does not have a strong preference in either direction. A preference may change with the context and/or relationships. In some situations {0} is more motivated by the recognition from others than by the pursuit and achievement of the goal or objective. In other situations {0} is more motivated by the opportunity to pursue and achieve the valued goal or objective more than being recognized for the efforts made. </entry><entry key="profile.motivation.tastcompletion.process.equal">{0} does not have a strong preference in either direction. A preference may change with the context and/or relationships. In some situations {0} is more motivated by clear definition and completion of the task. There is a sense of satisfaction when the work is complete, but possibly a frustration when it is not. In other situations {0} is more motivated by a preference to do the work well and stay with the process at hand. What is being done and how it is done are both important. Completing the task is not necessary to feel motivated or rewarded. Upon completion of a task or project {0} is usually ready to address the next process.  </entry><entry key="profile.motivation.recievedirection.greater.text">{0} is motivated by receiving direction from others rather than the opportunity to explore, dialogue on ideas, strategies, vision and challenges.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.hygiene.greater.text">{0} is not as motivated by the challenge of achievement, recognition, advancement, and overcoming significant obstacles. {0} is motivated more by an attractive environment, job security, appropriate compensation, adequate supervision, and satisfactory work conditions.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.freedom.consistency.equal">{0} does not have a strong preference either direction. A preference may change with the context and/or relationships. In some situations, {0} is more motivated by having the consistency or familiarity of predictable routines. In other situations, {0} may be more motivated by the freedom and latitude to make the decisions, adjustments and take action on matters deemed important.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.recievedirection.exchange.equal">{0} does not have a strong preference either direction. A preference may change with the context and/or relationships. In some situations {0} is more motivated by the opportunity to explore as well as to dialogue on ideas, strategies, vision and challenges. In other situations {0} is more motivated by receiving direction from others rather than the opportunity to explore and dialogue on ideas, strategies, vision and challenges.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.self.other.affired.equal">{0} does not have a strong preference either direction. A preference may change with the context and/or relationships. In some situations {0} possesses an internal sense of adding value to the surrounding environment. In other situations {0} finds self-esteem more through appreciation, encouragement and support of significant others.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.accomplishment.greater.text">{0} is not as motivated by an attractive environment, job security, appropriate compensation, adequate supervision, and satisfactory work conditions. {0} is motivated more by the challenge of achievement, recognition, advancement, and overcoming significant obstacles.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.heading">MOTIVATION</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.why.how.message">IS {0} MOTIVATED?</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.affirmedbyothers.greater.text">{0} finds self-esteem more through appreciation, encouragement and support of significant others, rather than experiencing self-esteem based on an internal sense of bringing a valued contribution to the surrounding environment.</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.affliation.activity.equal">{0} does not have a strong preference in either direction. A preference may change with the context and/or relationships. In some situations {0} is more motivated by “who” is involved in a situation rather than “what” is being done. However, in other situations {0} is more motivated by “what” is being done more than “who” it may involve. </entry><entry key="profile.motivation.what.text">MOTIVATES {0}</entry><entry key="profile.motivation.recongnitioneffort.greater.text">{0} is motivated by the recognition from others more than the pursuit and achievement of the goal or objective.</entry></properties>