<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><!-- smartling.translate_paths = properties/entry --><!-- smartling.placeholder_format_custom = (mm/dd/yyyy)|(\[.+?\])|(\{.+?\})|(\d)|(%)|(-) --><properties><entry key="og.Erti.title">Emotional, relational and Team Intelligence (ERT-i)</entry><entry key="og.Competency.description">Competencies are the measurable skills, attitudes, or attributes that distinguish your personal level of performance. To excel in your specific position, you'll need a clear understanding of how your company's performance strategy ties to your individual achievements. In this section, intelligent tools and content give you insight and direction into performing at your best.</entry><entry key="og.Prism.title">Prism&amp;#174; Portrait</entry><entry key="og.ConflictManagement.description">The Conflict Mangement module gives insights into different conflict styles—competing, collaborating, avoiding, accommodating and compromising—which gives a deeper understanding of how you interact with others, allowing for more productive and harmonious relationships.</entry><entry key="og.Personality.description">Prism&amp;#174; captures multiple dimensions of each individual, including the personality shift that happens when someone is under pressure. A clearly articulated analysis, including easy-to-grasp data visualizers, illustrate these dimensions.</entry><entry key="og.CompetencyManager.title">Competency Manager</entry><entry key="og.Pulse.title">Pulse </entry><entry key="og.Hiring.description">Identify not only the right people, but the right teams and environments for them with tools that work across all hiring criteria. Qualitative and quantitative data reveal the attributes most critical to your organization’s success.</entry><entry key="og.Spectrum.title">Spectrum</entry><entry key="og.RelationShipAdvisor.title">Relationship Advisor </entry><entry key="og.Erti.description">Personalized development plans with a rich curriculum based on your unique strengths and focus areas. This plan offers a wealth of easy-to-digest content and a step-by-step guide to growing your emotional, relational and team intelligence (ERT-i™)—the attributes most critical to success.</entry><entry key="og.ProcessingBlueprint.description">Processing reveals how you consume and assess information in order to approach people, activities and causes in your life. Based on four distinct scales, these measurements offer a precise view of your approach to processing internal and external stimuli, which is especially constructive in team environments.</entry><entry key="og.DecisionMaking.description">The Decision Making module measures your unique style and rationale for making decisions. Based on four unique but intertwined decider scales—outward, inward, careful and rapid—each insight offers a deeper view into your thought processes and personal expectations.</entry><entry key="og.KnowledgeCenter.description">SurePeople’s rich library of hand picked knowledge-building content. All served up in snack-sized morsels, across a wide variety of topics from over seventy ERT-i practice areas. Browse through a curated collection of videos and articles from leading publishers in the Knowledge Center.</entry><entry key="og.OrganizationPlan.title">Learning Programs</entry><entry key="og.Motivation.description">The Motivation module uncovers why you’re motivated, how those motivations take shape and what incites you to action. The why, how and what will uncover a telling and comprehensive analysis that can help you manage and drive your engagement, performance and success at work. </entry><entry key="og.Hiring.title">Intelligent Hiring </entry><entry key="og.Spectrum.description">This dashboard view of all your people allows you to make personnel decisions based on data, not hunches, and reveals patterns of performance at the highest possible level. It goes deep into team dynamics to identify opportunities for improvements. See at a glance the personality makeup of your entire organization, filter by group or demographic, and explore the traits of specific people.</entry><entry key="og.Pulse.description">Launch an anonymous survey with Pulse. Send it to the entire organization or just specific groups to determine employee satisfaction. It’s pre-filled with questions that assess your company’s health on measures of culture, engagement and leadership. Or, customize your own pulse to pull feedback and insights from anywhere in your workforce.</entry><entry key="og.PrismLens.description">The Prism&amp;#174; Lens is a powerful way to learn how others perceive you. How you're perceived is significant for growing your emotional, relational and team intelligence (ERT-i™). Each Lens result will uncover ERT-i opportunities by affecting the weighting of practice areas in your development plan.</entry><entry key="og.FundamentalNeeds.description">The Fundamental Needs module measures your desire to maintain control, retain security or achieve significance. We all have personal and professional needs that contribute to our outlook, attitude and behavior. Having these insights gives you a deeper understanding of your own drivers.</entry><entry key="og.CompetencyManager.description">Apply your company’s core competencies to the learning programs of all employees and to the criteria by which their performance will be measured. Target your organization’s competencies to specific roles and learning needs. Core competencies direct each and every employee to a series of actions designed to improve performance.</entry><entry key="og.Prism.description">The Prism&amp;#174; portrait reveals insights into nearly every aspect of your emotional, relational and team intelligence (ERT-i). This highly relevant and transformative data will provide you with critical information to impact your personal and professional performance, productivity and succeess.</entry><entry key="og.PrismLens.title">Prism&amp;#174; Lens</entry><entry key="og.Blueprint.description">Blueprint is your opportunity to express a personal mission statement that gives focus, motivation and accountability to your key initiatives, clearing the path from where you are now to where you want to be. It's a living document that allows real-time alignment with managers for expectation setting and tracking, with continual feedback and adjustment.</entry><entry key="og.Personality.title">Prism&amp;#174; Portrait - Personality</entry><entry key="og.Blueprint.title">Blueprint</entry><entry key="og.LearningStyle.description">The Learning Style module reveals how you process details and information within two distinct scales of learning: global and analytical. Understanding your specific learning style along with the different learning styles on your team will improve communication in any environment.</entry><entry key="og.OrganizationPlan.description">People development and organizational learning come together in organizational Learning Programs. Customized learning experiences are used to meet the highly specific needs of your business. Programs such as on-boarding, sales training, compliance and leadership training are delivered across teams, departments or the entire workforce.</entry><entry key="og.KnowledgeCenter.title">Knowledge Center</entry><entry key="og.RelationShipAdvisor.description">Relationship Advisor is a powerful tool that matches up other people's Prism&amp;#174; portraits to your own to reveal possible relationship dynamics. It’s an intuitive solution for mitigating conflicts and managing to collaborative outcomes. In other words, it works for people, not just the person.</entry><entry key="og.Competency.title">Competencies</entry><!-- smartling.sltrans = notranslate --><entry key="og.RelationShipAdvisor.url">/sp/prism/relationship-advisor</entry><entry key="og.OrganizationPlan.url">/sp/goalsOrg#/organization</entry><entry key="og.CompetencyManager.url">/sp/admin/competency/manager</entry><entry key="og.Prism.url">/sp/profile</entry><entry key="og.KnowledgeCenter.url">/sp/trainingLibrary</entry><entry key="og.Erti.url">/sp/goals#/practice</entry><entry key="og.PrismLens.url">/sp/feedback </entry><entry key="og.KnowledgeCenter.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/KnowledgeCenter.png</entry><entry key="og.Competency.url">/sp/competency/home#/profiles</entry><entry key="og.CompetencyManager.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/CompetencyManager.png</entry><entry key="og.Prism.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/Prism.png</entry><entry key="og.OrganizationPlan.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/LearningProgram.png</entry><entry key="og.Pulse.url">/sp/pulse</entry><entry key="og.Pulse.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/Pulse.png</entry><entry key="og.Personality.url">/sp/profile#/personality</entry><entry key="og.Competency.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/Competency.png</entry><entry key="og.Blueprint.url">/sp/blueprint#/publish</entry><entry key="og.RelationShipAdvisor.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/RelationShipAdvisor.png</entry><entry key="og.PrismLens.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/PrismLens.png</entry><entry key="og.Erti.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/Erti.png</entry><entry key="og.Hiring.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/Hiring.png</entry><entry key="og.Hiring.url">/sp/hiring</entry><entry key="og.Personality.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/Personality.png</entry><entry key="og.Spectrum.url">/sp/spectrum</entry><entry key="og.Spectrum.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/Spectrum.png</entry><entry key="og.Blueprint.imageUrl">/sp/resources/images/og/Blueprint.png</entry><!-- smartling.sltrans = translate --></properties>