<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><!-- smartling.translate_paths = properties/entry --><!-- smartling.placeholder_format_custom = (mm/dd/yyyy)|(\[.+?\])|(\{.+?\})|(\d)|(%)|(-) --><properties><entry key="profile.processing.intutive.text">&lt;li&gt;Prefers imagining new possibilities and opportunities in life situations&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Definitely likes opportunities to be creative and inventive&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Jumps in anywhere and tends to pass over the steps&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;May skip directions and tends to follow intuitive hunches&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Likes change and variety in the job and personal life&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Asks "What could I do if there are no limitations?"&lt;/li&gt; </entry><entry key="profile.processing.cognitive.heading">{0}% HEAD (COGNITIVE)</entry><entry key="profile.processing.internal.heading">{0}% INTERNALLY ENERGIZED</entry><entry key="profile.processing.trait.message">&lt;p&gt; A 50/50 result means that an individual's relation to their environment switches depending on the context of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.processing.spontaneous.heading">{0}% SPONTANEOUS</entry><entry key="profile.processing.concrete.heading">{0}% CONCRETE PROCESSOR</entry><entry key="profile.processing.cognitive.affective.summary">People use both their head and heart in making decisions but typically prefer and are better at one over the other. The person that prefers the &lt;strong&gt;head (cognitive)&lt;/strong&gt; function tends to make decisions based on what seems to be logical with objective information. This does not mean that the individual never makes decisions based on his heart. A person that prefers the &lt;strong&gt;heart (affective)&lt;/strong&gt; function in making decisions is likely to be more person-centered and/or value-centered. This does not mean that this person is overly emotional or illogical. It is not suggesting that the individual will never make a decision based on his head. </entry><entry key="profile.processing.vs">{0} vs. {1}</entry><entry key="profile.processing.affective.text">&lt;li&gt;Decides with the heart&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Goes by a sense of personal convictions&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Concerned for relational harmony&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Emotionally participates&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;May seem fuzzy-minded and emotional to the cognitive person&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.processing.external.text">&lt;li&gt;Energized by people&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Extroverted&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Acts, then possibly reflects&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Is often friendly and talkative&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Easy to get to know&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;More expressive and unrestrained&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Needs engaging activity&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Discovers thought as words are spoken&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;May seem shallow to the introvert&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Processes information outwardly&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.processing.concrete.text">&lt;li&gt;Prefers handling the practical matters of life situations&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Likes things that are definite and can be measurable&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Starts at the beginning, taking one step at a time&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Reads instructions and notices the details of a given situation&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Likes set procedures and the established routines&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Asks "What do I do in this situation?"&lt;/li&gt; </entry><entry key="profile.processing.summary">&lt;strong&gt;{0}&lt;/strong&gt; is {1} energized and {5} takes in information {2}. {6} makes decisions with {3} and {5} relates to the external world in {4} manner.</entry><entry key="profile.processing.concrete.intutive.summary">At any given time a person is either taking in information or making decisions based upon information already received. Using concrete or intuitive data are two ways of perceiving information. The &lt;strong&gt;concrete&lt;/strong&gt; processor prefers to utilize what can be actually seen, heard, touched, tasted, or smelled, rather than counting on the possibilities of what could be. The &lt;strong&gt;intuitive&lt;/strong&gt; processor prefers to gather information by application and thinking through as many different scenarios as possible. </entry><entry key="profile.processing.external.heading">{0}% EXTERNALLY ENERGIZED</entry><entry key="profile.processing.orderly.text">&lt;li&gt;Prefers an organized lifestyle, tends to organize what is important and may let other things go&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Likes definite order, structure and knowing what is to happen next&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Likes to have life under control and somewhat predictable&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Likes to have clearly defined limits and categories&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Feels comfortable establishing closure and getting something completed&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Enjoys deadlines and likes to plan in advance to prevent undue pressure&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;May seem demanding, rigid and uptight to the spontaneous type of individual&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.processing.spontaneous.text">&lt;li&gt;Prefers a flexible lifestyle and can adjust with the changes in life's situations&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Likes going with the flow and rolling with the punches&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Prefers to experience life as it happens&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Likes the freedom to be able to explore with minimum limits&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Meets deadlines by the last minute rush with a touch of suspense&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Fulfills tasks by a last minute sprint to the finish line&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;May seem disorganized, messy and irresponsible to the orderly type of individual&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.processing.intutive.heading">{0}% INTUITIVE PROCESSOR</entry><entry key="profile.processing.cognitive.text">&lt;li&gt;Decides with the head&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Goes with what seems to make sense&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Concerned for truth and justice&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Objectivity is important&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;May seem aloof and condescending to the affective person&lt;/li&gt; 			</entry><entry key="profile.processing.external.intenral.summary">&lt;strong&gt;Internally&lt;/strong&gt; energized and &lt;strong&gt;externally&lt;/strong&gt; energized are two different ways of relating to our environment. A person who is &lt;strong&gt;internally&lt;/strong&gt; energized prefers to focus on the inner world of ideas and thought. Time alone for reflection is important. This person is not necessarily shy or unsociable. However, the &lt;strong&gt;externally&lt;/strong&gt; energized person prefers to focus on people and activities, drawing energy from the external world, or those things in which he is involved. </entry><entry key="profile.processing.heading">PROCESSING</entry><entry key="profile.processing.orderly.heading">{0}% ORDERLY</entry><entry key="profile.processing.internal.text">&lt;li&gt;Energized by inner experiences&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Introverted&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Reflects, then possibly acts&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Is often reserved and quiet&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;May sometimes be harder to get to know&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;More private and restrained&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Needs privacy&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Thinks before speaking and acting&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;May seem withdrawn to the extrovert&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Processes information inwardly&lt;/li&gt;</entry><entry key="profile.processing.affective.heading">{0}% HEART (AFFECTIVE)</entry><entry key="profile.processing.orderly.spontaneous.summary">&lt;strong&gt;Orderly&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;spontaneous&lt;/strong&gt; reflect different lifestyle orientations by which people relate to the external world. A person who has an &lt;strong&gt;orderly&lt;/strong&gt; preference will generally relate to life by being more decisive, planned, structured and organized. Whereas, the person who is more &lt;strong&gt;spontaneous&lt;/strong&gt; in preference will generally relate to life by being more flexible, adaptable, curious and quick to embrace the change that may come his way.</entry></properties>