<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><!-- smartling.translate_paths = properties/entry --><!-- smartling.placeholder_format_custom = (mm/dd/yyyy)|(\[.+?\])|(\{.+?\})|(\d)|(%)|(-) --><properties><entry key="profile.spectrum.Motivator.description">Catalysts possess a natural ability to work with others. They can talk about anything with anyone, and use their persuasive verbal skills to inspire others. With an effervescent personality and a good sense of humor, they are often suitable for situations that require an ability to sell concepts or ideas. By conducting business in a friendly manner, Catalysts can transform customers and clients into friends. Catalysts are often inspiring, even if not in a formal leadership role. When acting as a leader, they inspire others and guide them towards larger goals by letting them manage important details. Catalysts are naturally enthusiastic, causing them to charge ahead on a project as they are drawn to the big picture. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.Leadership">Leads by being productive, keeping the activity moving in a timely fashion, and by being direct with those who are falling behind.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] is driven and confident, with an ability to charge ahead despite the obstacles. {1} views resistance and opposition as a challenge and is most effective when innovation and results are important.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.JobMatch">Since the NAVIGATOR personality seeks to be logical, accurate, practical and thorough, [Name] may function most effectively when the work environment is structured and organized. {1} works at {4} best when given independence and presented with problems and challenges to tackle. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: analyze, be accurate and in control, build and create; critique and improve, decide, develop, direct, initiate solutions and manage; organize, plan, process, perform quality control and research facts; solve problems, work with objects, work with data, supervise and think things through. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] possesses a hard, goal-driven orientation. {1} tends to charge ahead against all resistance and obstacles. Fear is not a common emotion as {0} seems to thrive on challenges and attack them with intense determination. The only thing {0} fears is loss of control or freedom to achieve the desired results.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Visionary">https://vimeo.com/175366704</entry><entry key="profile.personality.EmotionalPosture">EMOTIONAL POSTURE</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.EmotionalPosture">May be restrained in expression and is willing to accept aggression.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.underPressure.summary">The SurePeople Personality Portrait Under Pressure describes how we posture when under stress or pressure.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Leadership">LEADERSHIP</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] wants to know exactly what is expected in order to do the job well and accurately. {1} needs a relaxed manager or supervisor who is available to discuss key moves and who will be supportive during difficult situations. {1} has a desire to work with team members who are friendly and do not mind an unhurried pace. [Name] wants work associates to be personally interested and to express sincere appreciation for {4} contributions.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.UneasyWhen">There is failure to achieve the standards or when the ability to influence is diminished.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is easygoing, friendly, relaxed and independent. {1} is generally a nice and mild person who poses no threat and is difficult to dislike. People may come to {2} with problems because of {4} loyalty, empathy and ability to listen. Suggestions are likely to be offered in an indirect, offhanded way. Abruptness is rare.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.MobilityPreference">Desires a variety of projects. Seeks a constant flurry of activity and change.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">{1} may see others with a similar personality as territorial. Conflict may ensue over control. {1} may be turned off by â&#128;&#156;too much talkâ&#128;&#157; and â&#128;&#156;not enough actionâ&#128;&#157;. {1} may see some people as being less motivated or trying to stall the process with trivial or excessive details.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.Over-uses">Can go overboard with ingenuity. May experience difficulty trying to balance {4} interactions with people with finding adequate time to prepare.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.type">Adaptable</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.DrivingIdeal">A new opportunity, obstacle or challenge to overcome.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.Over-uses">May be overly tenacious.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.summary4">When {4} feelings are hurt or when {4} personal convictions are violated, [Name] may become caustic. {1} may be impatient when personal standards are not met. Learning to relax and finding a moderate pace would be beneficial.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.summary3">From one moment to another, [Name] can move from being precisely detailed in {4} approach to having little or no concern for the details. Even though {0} may be direct, aggressive and competitive in accomplishing a particular objective, others will still view {2} positively because of {4} considerate nature. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.NotableCharacteristics">Others may view [Name] as being positive, persuasive and the â&#128;&#156;life of the partyâ&#128;&#157;. Talking may be more important than listening. There is a tendency to be friendly as well as argumentative and persistent in the desire to achieve personal objectives. {1} is not afraid of new activities, challenges or people. {1} may thrive on taking calculated risks and has a deep desire for acceptance among peers.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.summary2">[Name] is likely to have a natural interest in detailed strategies that will accomplish an established goal. {1} can communicate the desired â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; and help others visualize the necessary steps needed to accomplish the goal. {1} involves others in a task or project through persuasion. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.summary1">Individuals with a INFLUENCER personality portrait possess opposing behavioral characteristics. As a INFLUENCER, [Name] is a critical thinker who utilizes persuasive verbal skills to inspire others to {4} cause, and can have little reservation about expressing an opinion or criticism. {1} possesses an effervescent personality and a good sense of humor. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.EmotionalPosture">Desires to keep pace with others in areas of performance.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.AssessesOthersBy">Their ability to verbalize and their flexibility and adaptability.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.MotivationalStyle">Rewarding, charming, inspiring, intimidating and giving direction.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.SummaryOfStrengths">Independent, result-oriented, confident, problem-solver and direct.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.SummaryOfStrengths">Dependable, patient, loyal, cooperative and a good listener.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] seeks open recognition from others and desires to be liked by associates. {1} prefers environments that place a high value on friendliness and familiarity. {1} desires to be outgoing, alert, tactful and unassuming and has an internal drive to seek a work environment that will offer prestige.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] may judge others with strong personalities as &amp;ldquo;know-it-alls&amp;rdquo; who initiate plans without considering important details and procedures. In such instances, [Name] may become territorial over who is more correct. {1} may view others as inaccurate, disorganized, embellishing or boastful and may also be concerned with others not having the correct information to make good decisions.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.UneasyWhen">There is a loss of power or influence. Fears being too soft in certain situations.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.JobMatch">The PIONEER is a “take charge” kind of person, so [Name] functions most effectively when presented with opportunities or challenges to express new or creative ideas with a minimum of problem-solving details. Because of {4} influential nature, {0} functions best when given the opportunity to meet people. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be active, humorous and in charge; verbalize, communicate, create, decide, develop and direct; entertain, gain recognition, influence and initiate solutions; lead others, manage, network, perform, solve problems and supervise.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.EmotionalPosture">Tends to be cautious and restrained. Wants to do things properly and competently.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.summary3">[Name] has the ability to discover information that others have a tendency to overlook. {1} is generally not a risk-taker, but rather, takes calculated risks based on the facts. {1} is inclined to hold {2}self and others to high standards and has the tendency to be a perfectionist. With the proper work ethic and skills, [Name] can help maintain high standards in {4} work environment. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.summary2">[Name] can be very conscientious and thorough when performing work that requires attention to detail and accuracy. Because {0} tends to prefer a predictable environment, having a clearly defined job description is important. {1} prefers to have specifics on what is expected, how much time is involved and on what basis the work is likely to be evaluated. When it comes to decision-making, {0} may take considerable time to gather and analyze detailed information before deciding. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.summary1">Individuals with an ARCHITECT personality portrait are precise, systematic workers and thinkers who tend to follow procedures both at work and in their personal lives. As an ARCHITECT, [Name] has a soft side that is typically modest and willing to accommodate. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.Over-uses">Being fully absorbed in the task with a tendency to become too self-reliant.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.RecommendedImprovements">[Name] dislikes having to give direct orders and can be too lenient with marginal workers. There is also a possibility of holding grudges against those who are critical of {2}. [Name] can struggle with disorganization, overlooking key aspects while becoming easily distracted so it would help to take time to plan and write down details to avoid being distracted. {1} may be too optimistic at times and need to focus on being more realistic. Seeking counsel from others may help think things through as {0} may be inclined to act before thinking.</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Researcher.description">Researchers are objective and analytical, and will calmly, steadily pursue a path towards a fixed goal. They are likely to be successful due to their determination, organization and a persistence to follow through on projects. Researchers desire tangible results while adhering to a high level of excellence. They strive to achieve defined agendas and objectives and tend to respond with logic more than emotions. Researchers shine when it comes to challenges that require the application of factual data and analysis to form a conclusion. Their strength of personality and desire to get things right leads their high personal standards and a prudently cautious approach to decision-making.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.RecommendedImprovements">[Name] tends to be carefully aggressive, tensely tactful, self-critical and overly serious. {6} high standards and critical nature may be problematic. There is a tension between the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; and getting the details together that may leave {2} struggling with indecision. The impact this has on others is stronger than {0} may realize. {1} either empower others with {4} strong personality or leaves them feeling hurt and criticized.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.JobMatch">JOB MATCH</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.DrivingIdeal">Possesses a driving desire to be correct and accurate.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.type">Powerful/Versatile/Adaptable</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.EnvironmentalStressors">The confinement of routines, processing detailed information and lacking access to people. Tends to over-commit.</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Actuary.description">Scientists are exceptionally detail-oriented and analytical. They have a strong need to get things just right and remain highly focused on that goal. Scientists possess a natural desire to think critically and to act based on correctness, accuracy and well-researched facts. This approach has a strong impact on their decision-making process, as they seek accuracy and logic and will explore all possible options before arriving at a conclusive decision. Scientists have a very strong task orientation and prefer a peaceful work environment. Their desire to be conscientious and principled is well-intentioned and can positively impact the work environment.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.underPressure.type">{0}</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Tough_N_Tender.description">Tough &amp; Tenders are often motivated by deeply felt convictions, objectives and goals. They are likely to possess a strong internal drive for accomplishment and apply the necessary pressure to attain desired results. When Tough &amp; Tenders are confident that the job will be done right, they will delegate tasks to those they trust. Their ambition indicates that they also hold high personal standards, which translates well in their work. Tough &amp; Tenders have a strong drive for achievement but can also be socially driven. They are supportive and possess a sensitive side that may not always be apparent.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Others may see {2} as disinterested or â&#128;&#156;on a missionâ&#128;&#157;. Those with soft personalities may see {2} as insensitive, self-centered or stubborn. Detailed people may perceive {2} as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.CommunicatingWith">Since the SCIENTIST is motivated by logic, not emotions, [Name] resists change unless {0} understands the reasons behind it. Provide well-researched details, facts and data to explain the required change.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] needs a manager who will tap into {4} creative flow and put {4} better ideas into practice. {1} needs a leader who will help get things finished and initiate new projects. It is important to have a manager who is direct and with whom {0} can be direct. A passive or carefree manager is not going to work. {1} needs challenging assignments that will be stimulating and a manager who reminds {2} to soften {4} approach.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Some people may wonder why [Name] isn''t more aggressive at times. Others may see {2} as overly sensitive and lacking initiative. Those with more energetic personalities may have to fight the impulse to light a fire under {2} to work at what they consider to be a more suitable pace.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.WhenPressured">Can become restless, impatient and critical.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Generally seeks work opportunities that let {2} express creative ideas and influence, entertain and impress people. Dislikes routines and details.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.UneasyWhen">There is a need to confront other people or when involved in conflict with others. This can prohibit {2} from seeking a supervisory role.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Enjoys challenges, variety and the opportunity to influence/inspire others. May strive for prestige and recognition.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.summary4">Due to {4} relationship-driven approach, [Name] may need help establishing and attaining realistic deadlines on certain tasks. {6} strong ability to work well with people can be a great asset, but it can also impede managerial tasks.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.summary3">At times, the AMBASSADOR can be too indirect, posing problems when it is time to give orders or make demands to address potential conflict. As such, being comfortable confronting others would contribute significantly to [Name]â&#128;&#153;s potential. Similarly, the AMBASSADOR responds well to encouragement but may take criticism as a personal affront. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.summary2">[Name] maintains relationships with diplomacy, personal warmth and understanding, and is likely to solve problems by listening and offering suggestions. {1} typically notices the strengths in others and maintain long-term relationships. {1} is suited for jobs where a strong social approach is essential, and may go to great lengths to avoid making waves in both personal and work relationships. This may result in [Name] being overly tolerant of those who are unproductive, which makes it difficult to confront and discipline those who underperform.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.summary1">Individuals with an AMBASSADOR personality portrait naturally network well with others and have an ability to talk about anything with anyone. As an AMBASSADOR, [Name] approaches life with a â&#128;&#156;people come firstâ&#128;&#157; philosophy, rather than being task-oriented or objective-oriented.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Result-oriented, with a global perspective that allows {2} to see the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157;. May take charge, define goals and apply the pressure that gets results. What some see as barriers, {0} may view as challenges to overcome or puzzles to solve.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.MobilityPreference">Enjoys a variety of people and activities in the schedule. Without variety, {0} can become bored.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.EmotionalPosture">Possesses two opposite postures. At times, persistent, determined and industrious, displaying frustration when goals are thwarted. Other times, exhibits a soft, relational and easygoing demeanor. This may be confusing to work colleagues and family members, especially children.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.RelationalTaskOrientation">A â&#128;&#156;people personâ&#128;&#157; who may become so totally engrossed in the group dynamic that {0} can lose focus on the work. Can place greater priority on helping others solve problems than being committed to a given task.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.DrivingIdeal">Strives to win with style.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.PerformanceImprovement">Be a more collaborative team member and improve {4} ability to receive negative feedback graciously.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.SummaryOfStrengths">Analytical, detailed, organized, cautious, accurate, loyal dependable and cooperative.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.RelationalTaskOrientation">Primarily relational but will complete a task in order to be pleasing to work associates or customers.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.Over-uses">An indirect approach, tolerance and patronizing others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.DrivingIdeal">To maintain independence and a position of dominance.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.EnvironmentalStressors">Feeling excluded from social interactions and not having adequate time for reflection. Can also become stressed when disapproved by others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.DisagreeingWith">Provide specific examples of how an idea, concept or plan has worked in other settings. Take a team approach and reassure [Name] of personal relationships as disagreements may be interpreted as personal rejection. Assurances of being â&#128;&#156;in this togetherâ&#128;&#157; will help {2} relax and accommodate something new and different.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Variety that allows time to interact with people, but also adequate time alone to prepare.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Follows through in order to maintain steadiness and loyalty in the workplace. Typically does not â&#128;&#156;rock the boatâ&#128;&#157; and gets along well with most people. Maintains a steady pace and is consistent, predictable and a short-term planner.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.WhenPressured">May become frustrated or impatient and is likely to perform the job alone rather than delegate the work to others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Likely to be a good listener with a team player spirit. Cooperates well and has a positive and easygoing attitude, promoting harmony among co-workers. Generally likes to serve others and create harmony.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Work Environment Contribution</entry><entry key="profile.personality.EnvironmentalStressors">ENVIRONMENTAL STRESSORS</entry><entry key="profile.personality.dimension.text">SurePeople four dimension personality type:</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.EnvironmentalStressors">The confinement of routines, processing detailed information and a lack of access to people. Possibly has a tendency to over-commit.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.EnvironmentalStressors">Disorganization and abrupt changes without adequate preparation time. Emotional displays by others may be frustrating.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is generally perceived as easygoing, friendly, relaxed and independent. {1} has a deep desire for acceptance among peers and probably has many friends. {1} is nonthreatening, sympathetic, hard to dislike and a good listener. {1} is likely to offer suggestions in indirect, offhanded ways. Abruptness is rare.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">{1} may view work associates with strong personalities as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. {1} may be concerned that others who do not have the details cannot make good decisions may feel that others do not appreciate high standards or expectations.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.EmotionalPosture">Does not back down easily and is not intimidated by aggression. Tends to minimize personal need for affirmation.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.video.Encourager">https://vimeo.com/175366575</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.CommunicatingWith">Provide {2} with the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; before providing any explanations, details and concerns. Since the INSTRUCTOR is not by nature a good listener, compose thoughts into a short memo for {2}, detailing the problems, options and recommended actions. {1} will likely be open to personal testimony and endorsement, so persuade {2} with information about who is involved and who thinks it is a good idea. Also show how the project will be fun and interesting. Remind {2} of the details often or they may be forgotten.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] seeks a job that provides a familiar, consistent and predictable environment. Time to adjust to change is important. {1} needs to focus on one job at a time and do it thoroughly. {1} usually prefers to work at one place rather than traveling overnight. [Name] strives to maintain close relationships with work associates and is usually very loyal.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.summary5">[Name] is likely to use {4} persuasive verbal skills to recruit others for a cause. Even though {0} can sometimes overwhelm others, {0} is liked by {4} work associates. Hidden within {4} strong personality is a softer and more empathetic approach that is not immediately apparent to most.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.summary4">In a formal leadership role, [Name] may inspire or persuade others to help with repetitive work processes or manage the details. However, some people may have conflicted feelings working with {2}. On one hand, people can be strongly attracted to {4} social skills and confidence, but may also be distanced by the power of {4} personality. Some may feel exhausted by [Name]â&#128;&#153;s stamina to accomplish {4} goals. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.summary3">[Name] is usually clear on the results desired but may not always verbalize them immediately. For example, {0} may offer security to those who seek a predictable environment. The STRATEGIST tends to focus on the big picture and overlook the details; therefore [Name] should look for detailed or analytical people to help {2} overcome the challenges in a project or situation. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.summary2">As a STRATEGIST, [Name] may exhibit a unique capacity to move people and tasks in a forward direction because of {4} vision and social skills. {1} often possesses the ability to identify the motives of others and rally them toward a pre-determined goal. Whether through formal responsibility or casual contact, [Name] leads others with an energetic personality and a plan. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.summary1">Individuals with a STRATEGIST personality portrait exhibit a unique mix of patterns and are some of the strongest among the personality profiles. But disguised in the mix may be a softer, more peaceful demeanor. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.DrivingIdeal">Getting the approval of others and gaining relationship influence.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.EnvironmentalStressors">Routine, disorganization and the loss of ability to control the quality and direction of the work environment.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.Leadership">May exhibit a leadership style that defines the goal and then motivates others to work together to accomplish that goal.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.MobilityPreference">Good at working on one project for long periods of time.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.UneasyWhen">Losing in a competitive interaction or when perceived poorly by others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">{1} may see those with strong personalities as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. {1} may build resentment towards someone whom {0} deems to be pushy. Verbally aggressive people may be annoying and wear {2} down.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">Being ambitious, [Name] may not be easy to manage. Give {2} freedom to run things the way {0} deems appropriate, but remind {2} that limitations to authority exist. {1} works best with a friendly supervisor with whom open discussion and honesty are expected and accepted.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.CommunicatingWith">Since [Name] is motivated by achieving goals, discuss the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; first. Do not get carried away by elaborating on the details before the end goal is clear. Provide the reasons for change and a course of action with well-researched facts and data. {1} is inclined to think about the practical details of any goal or objective, so {0} may also play a role as a change agent when change makes sense. Use diplomacy and a non-controversial tone.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">MOST FAVORABLE WORK ENVIRONMENT</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.DisagreeingWith">Carefully document the position with facts and data that have been well researched, offering proof. Then ask [Name] to consider the case. Do not push too hard, but rather, provide {2} time to consider and process the evidence. {1} can be highly committed to new ideas but postponing an immediate decision may cause {2} to lose {4} emotional attachment to the idea. Delaying the decision for even a day or two may open the door for {2} to accept other ideas.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.JobMatch">Since the CONNECTOR personality functions most effectively when given the opportunity to influence, meet or entertain people, [Name] needs variety and opportunities to express new and creative ideas without a lot of detail-oriented work. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be active and humorous; communicate, entertain, gain recognition and influence; network, perform, relate and verbalize.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.SummaryOfStrengths">Verbal, persuasive, enthusiastic, analytical and cautious.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Some may view [Name] as overly concerned with the details. On some occasions, {0} may be seen as playing the role of the â&#128;&#156;expertâ&#128;&#157; and can come across as a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157;. Some may feel competitive towards {2} because of {4} influential nature and ability to assemble facts. Others can judge {2} as fickle because of {4} swings between being logical and very emotional.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] is prone to view others with a similar personality as territorial. Conflict may ensue over control. {1} can be turned off by too much talk and not enough results, and may view others as less motivated or holding up the process with trivial and excessive attention to details. {1} may be jealous of someone else receiving more attention and may view others as being too sensitive, pessimistic or slow in their work.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.Over-uses">May tend to be overly tenacious.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] may view work associates with strong personalities as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. {1} may be concerned that others who do not have the details cannot make good decisions and prone to view others as less motivated, disorganized or inaccurate.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Prefers a conflict-free setting and seeks the opportunity to encourage and support others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.Over-uses">Can get stuck on procedures and fail-safe controls. May exhibit a â&#128;&#156;this is how it''s supposed to be doneâ&#128;&#157; attitude. There may be an over-dependence on people and processes that have worked well in the past. Abrupt changes can be greeted by resistance or reluctance.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Even-paced work that is organized, structured and provides clear guidelines. Time is needed to think things through. Very likely appreciates precision and work associates who value accuracy.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.SummaryOfStrengths">Independent, detailed, result-oriented, confident, and a problem-solver who is likely to be direct in {4} approach.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.primary.heading">PRIMARY PERSONALITY</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.Over-uses">May appear blunt, critical, aloof or condescending.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Utilizes creative ideas and information to influence, energize and entertain people. Has the ability to accomplish goals and objectives by motivating other people.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.type">Powerful/Precision</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.MotivationalStyle">Offering understanding and empathy in relationships.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is generally assertive, action-oriented and very independent. With a flair for adventure, {0} is typically determined and not easily intimidated. Being self-motivated and determined, {0} thrives on solving difficult problems with brain power and tenacity.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.UneasyWhen">Having to deal with large groups of people or faced with the need to sell abstract ideas.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.WhenPressured">May become argumentative and choose a passive-aggressive approach.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.RelationalTaskOrientation">Tends to be very task-oriented but also relates well to people. May experience tension between tasks and relationships.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.WhenPressured">Becomes overly flexible and intimate, using key friendships to accomplish what needs to get done.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.type">Versatile/Adaptable</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.user.personality.subheading">The SurePeople Primary Personality Portrait describes how [Name] represents {3} to others, as well as how others perceive {2} in stressful and non-stressful situations.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.AssessesOthersBy">Their ability to get things going and initiate activity.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.AssessesOthersBy">How they meet {4} standards.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Strives to be logical and is motivated to be precise, accurate, practical and thorough. Inclined to maintain standards and quality control. Likely to develop or possess a specific and specialized work area.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.SummaryOfStrengths">Direct, independent, ambitious, result-oriented, confident and adept at solving problems. Likely to demonstrate a willingness to tackle difficult or undefined projects.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] prefers to have detailed instructions and an exact job description that shows what is expected. {1} prefers to be included in decisions rather than make them independently of others. {1} tends to work best for a manager or supervisor who is available to discuss significant decisions and strategies.Â </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.RelationalTaskOrientation">Tends to be task-oriented, striving to understand systems and processes so they can propose how things â&#128;&#156;should beâ&#128;&#157;. Needs adequate time to assess problems and strategies, preferring to monitor facts and data to keep things on track.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.UneasyWhen">UNEASY WHEN </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">{1} may appear too sensitive by those with strong personalities, and insensitive or unbending by those with soft personalities. {1} may come across to some as being a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157;. Some may be confused by {4} tough-minded approach in some situations, and soft and adaptive approach in others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.CommunicatingWith">Since NAVIGATORS are motivated by logic and not emotion, [Name] resists change unless {0} understands the reasons behind it. Provide well-researched details, facts and data to explain the required change. Paint the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; before providing explanations.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Others may see [Name] as disinterested or â&#128;&#156;on a missionâ&#128;&#157;. Those with soft personalities may view {2} as insensitive, self-centered and bullish. Detail-oriented people may perceive {2} as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. Others might also find {2} to be disorganized, inaccurate or one who exaggerates facts.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.MobilityPreference">Can work in one place for an extended period of time while remaining focused on one project, though may prefer variety in {4} work.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.DrivingIdeal">Likes to achieve unique accomplishments.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Some may view [Name] as overly concerned with the details. On occasion, {0} may be perceived as rigid or unbending. Some may feel competitive towards {2} because of {4} influential nature and ability to assemble facts. Others may see {2} as fickle because of {4} logical approach in some instances and emotional approach at other times.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.DrivingIdeal">May prefer a position that offers status, influence, authority or prestige.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.AssessesOthersBy">How well they can verbalize their perspective.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.type">Precision/Versatile/Adaptable</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.summary4">[Name] is naturally enthusiastic, causing {2} to charge ahead on a project without considering the important details. Routine and regimentation can diminish {4} enthusiasm. It could be a mistake to overwhelm {2} with details, as {0} is drawn to the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157;. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.summary3">[Name] is often inspiring, even if not in a formal leadership role. However, when acting as a leader, {0} may inspire or persuade others to help with repetitive work processes or manage the details. Some people may have conflicted feelings working with {2}. On one hand, people can be strongly attracted to {4} social skills and confidence; on the other hand, they may also be distanced by the power of {4} personality. Some may feel exhausted by [Name]â&#128;&#153;s stamina to accomplish {4} goals. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is determined, logical, tenacious and independent. {1} performs most effectively when working hard and is not prone to quick flashes of success. {1} analyzes and evaluates problems objectively and is inclined to follow leads and uncover hidden facts. {1} may dominate others at times but will usually do it with patience, taking nothing for granted. {1} is likely to be result-oriented and not afraid to voice an opinion.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.summary2">By conducting business in a friendly manner, [Name] can transform customers and clients into friends. However, {0} can be overly optimistic and overestimate {4} ability to bring people together to achieve the desired goal. Since maintaining a positive image is important, {0} may seek people-related assignments that provide the opportunity to shine. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.summary1">Individuals with a CATALYST personality portrait possess a natural ability to work with others. As a CATALYST, [Name] can talk about anything with anyone, and use {4} persuasive verbal skills to inspire others to {4} cause. With an effervescent personality and a good sense of humor, {0} is often suitable for situations that require an ability to sell products, concepts or ideas. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.AssessesOthersBy">Their objectivity, cognitive abilities and precision.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Possible Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.DrivingIdeal">Cultivates friendships, striving for acceptance from others. Seeks contentment.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Promoter.description">Building friendships in a variety of settings comes naturally to Connectors, as does maintaining an extensive network of contacts. They can be people magnets with a natural ability to attract others. Connectors lead with enthusiasm and desire, while building a positive social environment where maintaining contact with people is necessary. Because of the broad networks they establish, they're likely to have access to people who can be very helpful in a variety of different areas. Connectors possess the ability to promote ideas and inspire enthusiasm in others. They are usually optimistic and can form favorable conclusions without having all the details nailed down. This optimism allows them to embrace change and spontaneity.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.RelationalTaskOrientation">A â&#128;&#156;people personâ&#128;&#157; who may become so engrossed in communicating that there is a loss of focus on the task.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Capable of improving efficiency and achieving results by initiating change within an organization. Has great potential for vision and the synthesis of facts, events and concepts in order to develop long-range strategies.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">A well-organized work setting where accuracy, dependability and logic are valued and appreciated.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.summary4">[Name] is typically interested in achieving goals, thriving on challenges and making important advancements. Since {0} is focused on results, {0} could leave behind people who do not possess the same level of stamina and endurance. A lack of empathy may be expressed with an attitude of â&#128;&#156;just get over itâ&#128;&#157;.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.summary3">[Name] may sometimes use a direct and forceful approach to get things accomplished, resorting to manipulation to accomplish objectives and doing what it takes to overcome obstacles. {1} may also become belligerent when required to participate in group situations that are not conducive to an individualistic approach. In fact, some people may be intimidated by {4} tenacity and high expectations. [Name] has the capacity for the more difficult endeavors that are unsuitable for softer personalities.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.RelationalTaskOrientation">Relates well to people but under pressure, prioritizes tasks. Unusually motivated by succeeding in situations where others were not even willing to try.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.summary2">In a work environment, others may see [Name] as being on a mission. {1} is often forward-thinking in {4} approach, considering the next project before the current one is even completed. Being extremely independent and self-reliant, {0} may prefer to find {4} own solution to an obstacle and be relatively free from group constraints. Innovative solutions are often discovered because of {4} internal belief that there must be a better way.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.JobMatch">The TOUGH &amp; TENDER personality seeks to work at a steady pace, follow through on assignments and cooperate with others. As such, [Name] prefers work that is structured and organized. {1} is most effective when {0} is given authority, independence, challenges, problems to solve and obstacles to overcome. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be consistent and loyal; build, create, critique and improve; decide, develop, direct and focus on one task at a time; follow through, initiate solutions, manage and set a good example; work in one place, specialize and support others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.summary1">Individuals with a VISIONARY personality portrait exhibit some of the strongest personality characteristics. As a VISIONARY, [Name] may not always be fully aware of the impact {4} strong personality may have on work associates and others. {1} is typically a strong individualist who continually strives to seek new objectives and agendas. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.summary4">[Name] is likely to use {4} persuasive verbal skills to recruit others for a cause. Even though {0} can sometimes overwhelm others, {0} is liked by {4} work associates.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.summary3">In a formal leadership role, [Name] may inspire or persuade others to help with repetitive work processes or manage the details. Some people may have conflicted feelings working with {2}. On the one hand, people can be strongly attracted to {4} social skills and confidence, but may also be distanced by the power of {4} personality. Some may feel exhausted by [Name]â&#128;&#153;s stamina to accomplish {4} goals. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Others may see [Name] as very territorial. Conflict may occur over who is in control and who is correct. {1} may be seen as picky or pushy with a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. Others may see {2} as overbearing, demanding or unyielding.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.summary2">[Name] tends to focus on â&#128;&#156;the big pictureâ&#128;&#157; and overlook the details. {1} can possess the ability to identify the motives of others and direct {2} toward a pre-determined goal, applying the pressure necessary to obtain results.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.summary1">Individuals with an INSTRUCTOR personality portrait have some of the stronger personalities. As an INSTRUCTOR, [Name] has a desire to dramatically influence people as well as improve {4} surroundings. Whether through an assigned role or casual contact, {0} leads others by exerting energetic personality. While {4} leadership isn''t always assigned, {0} leads because {0} enjoys it and has a plan.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Others may see {2} as disinterested or â&#128;&#156;on a missionâ&#128;&#157;. Those with soft personalities may see {2} as insensitive, self-centered and bullish. Detail-oriented people may perceive {2} as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. Others might also find {2} to be disorganized, inaccurate or one who exaggerates facts.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.RecommendedImprovements">While [Name] can see the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157;, {0} may not fully understand the amount of detailed work that is required. Seeking feedback from work associates and friends who are more detail-oriented would help gain a better understanding of the steps involved in a particular process. [Name] can also struggle with disorganization and overlook key facts while distracted, so it would help to take time to plan, write down details and stay focused.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.MobilityPreference">Enjoys a balance between moderate change and consistency in their daily work activity. Has a strong desire to move around, which leads to diverse interpersonal relationships.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.CommunicatingWith">Since the PRAGMATIST is naturally logical, organized and accurate, [Name] may resist change unless there is an understanding of the reasons for change. Work associates should provide {2} with a rationale when making decisions by offering well-researched details, facts and data. Persuade {2} by conveying who is involved and who thinks it is a good idea. Communicate how the new idea is fun or interesting.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] prefers facts, figures and objects rather than working with people. To be successful, {0} may need to take additional time to weigh the pros and cons of each situation carefully, doing only one thing at a time.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.type">Versatile/Powerful</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.video.Innovator">https://vimeo.com/175366659</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.summary4">For [Name], a considerable amount of emotional energy can be spent maintaining a familiar and predictable environment. This may be a challenge to work associates who are innovative. Rapid change generally creates an uncomfortable environment for [Name], who is likely to achieve remarkable consistency in work performance when there is the opportunity to specialize within a predictable environment. Expressed appreciation and affirmations from work associates will go a long way in motivating {2}. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.summary3">[Name] is likely to lead by being helpful to those in the workplace who are considered {4} friends. There is an emotional need to keep the peace and {0} may become discouraged if the work setting contains conflict. {1} avoids tense situations, â&#128;&#156;making wavesâ&#128;&#157; or having to make a major change. Advanced warning of surprises or change allows {2} to make important adjustments and be more consistent. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.summary2">[Name] maintains a low profile by blending into work and social situations. {1} is usually reliable and works at a steady and predictable pace, keeping the peace and mediating among contentious people. {1} influences others with {4} accommodating nature, pleasant posture and consistent work performance. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.summary1">Individuals with an ALLY personality portrait are typically calm, modest and willing to accommodate others. As an ALLY, [Name] typically leads others and relates in a considerate and personal manner. </entry><entry key="profile.video.Designer">https://vimeo.com/175366597</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Utilizes creative ideas and information in order to influence and energize work associates. Can be proficient in an area of specialization as well as resolving social problems.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.WorkEnvironmentContribution">May offer loyalty and dependability to those in need, expressing concern and compassion with strong interpersonal skills. Promotes harmony between individuals and groups, and is a good listener.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.CommunicatingWith">Provide the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; before providing any explanations, details and concerns. Since VISIONARIES are not good listeners by nature, compose thoughts into a short memo for [Name] that details the problems, options and recommended actions. Otherwise thereâ&#128;&#153;s the danger of losing {4} attention with the details.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.MotivationalStyle">Rewarding, charming, inspiring, intimidating and giving direction.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] may see those with strong personalities as self-centered, territorial or insensitive. {1} can be turned off by too much talk or not enough results. {1} tries not to be an imposition, and in some situations, can feel judged by those who do not see things the same way.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.DrivingIdeal">High standards, determination and getting it right.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.RecommendedImprovements">RECOMMENDED IMPROVEMENTS </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.WhenPressured">May be too easily persuaded. May be more organized under pressure when there is a desire to make a good impression.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.RelationalTaskOrientation">RELATIONAL/TASK ORIENTATION</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.summary4">The PRAGMATIST is also known to be strong socially. That means [Name] can be conversant in a broad range of subjects and project a relaxed and diplomatic style. However, this can be perceived either positively as being â&#128;&#156;in the knowâ&#128;&#157;, or negatively as being a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157;. Underneath {4} social side is a person with high standards of personal performance. Valuing {4} own self-discipline, [Name] may judge others by these same personal standards and feel disappointed when {4} high expectations arenâ&#128;&#153;t met. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.summary3">[Name] can effortlessly change from being the fun-loving person one moment to being serious-minded the next. {1} tends to involve and include others through persuasion. {1} typically desires to be proficient in {4} work and gravitates toward a specialty area. This is caused by an underlying drive to be proficient in a specific area.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.summary2">[Name] possesses a natural desire for critical thinking, making decisions and carrying out actions based on detail, accuracy and correctness. {1} is outgoing and naturally enjoys being with people. Networking with others comes easily and {0} can usually talk about anything with anyone. The demonstration of these seemingly opposite postures can be confusing to some people. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.summary1">Individuals with a PRAGMATIST personality portrait exhibit a unique mix of personality patterns with seemingly opposing strengths. As a PRAGMATIST, [Name] may fluctuate between being serious and detailed-oriented, then switch to being very fun-loving and carefree. There may also be a less obvious â&#128;&#156;soft sideâ&#128;&#157;.</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Refiner.description">Architects are precise, systematic workers and thinkers who tends to follow procedures both at work and in their personal lives. They have a soft side that shows their modesty and willingness to accommodate others. They are conscientious and thorough when performing work that requires attention to detail and accuracy. Architects are exceptionally detail-oriented and often discover information that others have a tendency to overlook. They tend to prefer a predictable environment with specific expectations including how much time is allotted and on what basis the work is likely to be evaluated. When it comes to decision-making, they're known to be objective and informed thinkers that take time to gather and analyze data instead of jumping to conclusions. Architects take calculated risks based on facts and are inclined to maintain high standards in their work environment.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.DisagreeingWith">Carefully document facts and data that have been well researched. Offer proof before asking {2} to consider the case. Do not push too hard for an immediate decision. Allow time to consider the evidence, apply logic and process the information. Look for areas of agreement to serve as a foundation for change.</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Innovator.description">Strategists move people and tasks in a forward direction because of their vision and social skills. They often possess the ability to identify the motives of others and rally them toward a pre-determined goal. Whether through formal responsibility or casual contact, Strategists lead others with an energetic personality and a plan. They are intentional, goal-oriented, and focused on the big picture. In a formal leadership role, Strategists inspire and persuades others, as people are strongly attracted to their social skills and assertive personality. Strategists are likely to use their verbal skills to recruit others for a cause. Hidden within their strong personality is a softer and more empathetic approach that causes them to be liked by work associates.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] can be helpful in mobilizing people in a nonthreatening and low-pressure manner. {1} prefers a manager who is friendly and pleasant when things are going well, but who is supportive when the work situation is not going as expected. {1} desires a supervisor who will allow a free exchange of ideas, listen and provide feedback using a cordial tone. Addressing one another should be done on a first-name basis. Allowing for social interactions will go a long way in keeping {4} morale positive.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.MotivationalStyle">Being accountable for {4} own work and accomplishments.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.WhenPressured">Becomes overly compromising and sensitive. May be too trusting without discerning the unique differences in the work styles of others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.SummaryOfStrengths">Usually likes change and is quite verbal, persuasive, enthusiastic and optimistic.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] is prone to see others with a similar personality as territorial. Conflict may ensue over control. {1} can be turned off by too much talk and not enough results, and may see others as less motivated or holding up the process with trivial and excessive attention to details. {1} may be jealous of someone else receiving more attention and may see others as being too sensitive, pessimistic or slow in their work.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.OverUses">OVER-USES</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Encourager.description">Peacemakers relate exceptionally well to others and are strong networkers who strive to build a pleasant and productive work environment. Their primary approach to life is based on relationships rather than tasks or objectives. Peacemakers typically notice strengths in others and maintain long-term relationships. They leave a positive impression with their warmth, empathy and consideration. Peacemakers are likely to solve problems by listening and offering suggestions in a diplomatic, supportive manner and they're motivated by recognition for a job well done. When in a position of responsibility, Peacemakers excel at recognizing both the achievements of other group members and focusing on the quality of the work.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.RecommendedImprovements">For [Name], fretting and worrying over small matters can create a habit of checking and re-checking, which can take time and energy, as well as irritate others. {1} can be overly analytical and even a barrier to progress. It is suggested {0} learns to act quicker and focus on compromising for a good, rather than perfect, solution.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] is patient, personable, unassuming and steadfast. Regardless of the situation, {0} will generally advise others in a good-natured and pleasant way.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.Leadership">Tends to work alone on key projects in order to make sure they are done correctly. Exhibits leadership in a reserved and polite manner.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">{1} may judge others as being disorganized, less prepared, less accurate and unproductive. {1} is likely to feel offended by or lose respect for others who publicly criticize, embarrass or correct {2}.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.AssessesOthersBy">Their ability to effectively communicate.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.RecommendedImprovements">While friendly, [Name] may occasionally be viewed as inconsiderate. Suggest focusing on â&#128;&#156;listening to understandâ&#128;&#157; rather than â&#128;&#156;talking to convinceâ&#128;&#157;. {1} is likely to have a streak of independence and is reluctant to change {4} less desirable habits. Although {0} can see the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157;, {0} may not fully understand the level of detailed work required. Seeking feedback from more detailed-oriented work associates and friends would help {2} understand the process involved and achieve results.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] prefers working independently and can be counted on to be thorough and complete on follow-through. {1} needs the freedom to question, investigate and follow leads on matters that arouse {4} suspicion. {1} needs to move at {4} own pace and does not want people looking over {4} shoulder or keeping tabs on {2}. {1} aspires to high standards of performance that include quality control and thoroughness.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.WhenPressured">May become bored with routine or the status quo, and may act independently of a team or become irritated when restrained.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">{1} is prone to see others with a similar personality as territorial. Conflict may ensue over control. {1} can be turned off by too much talk and not enough results, and may see others as less motivated or holding up the process with trivial and excessive attention to details. {1} may also be jealous of someone else receiving more attention and may see others as being too sensitive, pessimistic or slow in their work.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.DrivingIdeal">Personal accomplishments that can be, at times, at the expense of group goals.</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Pragmatist.description">Pragmatists can be both serious and detailed-oriented, as well as fun-loving and carefree. They possess a desire for critical thinking, making decisions and taking action based on detail, accuracy and correctness. They are outgoing and naturally enjoy being with people. Networking with others comes easily as they can often talk about anything with anyone. They can be conversant in a broad range of subjects and project a relaxed and diplomatic style. Pragmatists tend to involve and engage others through persuasion. They typically desire to be proficient in their work and gravitate toward a specialty area. Pragmatists can be counted on to be consistent and reliable due to the fact that they hold high standards of personal performance and value self-discipline.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] is generally confident and will charge ahead despite obstacles. {1} may view resistance and opposition as challenges and is most effective when innovation and results are important. {1} is likely to have the stamina to sustain a fast pace and will expect others to keep up. Decisions are made quickly and easily with the recognition that some restraints or limitations are necessary. However, {0} will not let unnecessary restraints stop {2} from pressing toward the goal.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.DisagreeingWith">Carefully document the position with facts and data that have been well researched, offering proof. Then ask [Name] to consider the case. Do not push too hard; rather, give {2} time to consider and process the evidence. Remember, {0} needs time to process information so do not put {2} on the spot by embarrassing or correcting {2} publicly.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.RelationalTaskOrientation">Has a tendency to be very task-oriented with a preference for working with data and interacting one-on-one with people. May prefer to work alone in order to minimize interruptions even though {0} can be loyal and social.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.EmotionalPosture">May be naturally enthusiastic and trusting.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is friendly, dependable and loyal. {1} finds a steady pace that works and sticks with it. Having the opportunity to focus on a single task and developing skills in a specialty area is important. {1} generally works with a mild-mannered style.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.UneasyWhen">It is necessary to be â&#128;&#156;softâ&#128;&#157; or lenient on others when they believe that others are taking advantage of them. Or when the work pace seems to be moving too slowly.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.Leadership">First defines the goals, then offers enthusiasm in order to motivate others to perform. However, should be aware that others can feel used or manipulated because of {4} strong personality.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.Leadership">Leads by caring for others and by building good relationships. Sees the best in others and is very patient with co-workers.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.RelationalTaskOrientation">Strikes a good balance between committing to people and tasks, which makes {2} a potentially effective leader.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.MotivationalStyle">Objectivity, accuracy, thought organization, factual data and logical arguments.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.JobMatch">The SCIENTIST seeks to be logical, accurate, practical and thorough, so [Name] functions most effectively when {4} work environment is structured and organized. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: analyze, be accurate, review details, critique and improve, follow procedures, follow up on details, ensure quality, organize, perform identified tasks, plan with committees, research concepts and work with objects.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is positive, steady and systematic, and has a tendency to be direct and straightforward. {1} feels challenged by difficult problems that require logical analysis and as a result, may be perceived as intellectually curious. Since {0} is patient and deliberate, {0} may prefer working with things, rather than having to influence people. [Name] may become dissatisfied when searching for the best answer. {1} want to achieve, but may also want to be correct. Striving for both accomplishments and quality often leads others to see {2} as a perfectionist.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.summary4">When in task mode, some of [Name]â&#128;&#153;s work relationships may not receive the important attention and energy they deserve. There is a tendency to evaluate people and ideas on the basis of facts and logic. As such, [Name]â&#128;&#153;s ability to deal with others can be improved by trying to understand their perspectives and feelings. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.summary3">[Name] tends to respond with logic more than emotions and performs well with challenges that require the application of factual data and analysis to form a conclusion. {1} may not be especially interested in pleasing people as adherence to high personal standards can occasionally take precedence over relationships. Decision-making can be restrained by the need to explore all possible options before arriving at a conclusive decision. {6} strength of personality and desire to get things right may be perceived by others as being inflexible. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.summary2">[Name] desires tangible results and attaining a high level of excellence. {1} strives to achieve defined agendas and objectives. Others may need to get confrontational to change {4} direction. As a result, {0} could be perceived as opinionated or stubborn. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.summary1">Individuals with a RESEARCHER personality portrait exhibit opposing strengths and have complex personalities. As a RESEARCHER, [Name] is typically objective and analytical, and will calmly and steadily pursue a path towards a fixed goal. {1} is likely to be successful due to {4} determination, organization and a persistence to follow through on most projects.  </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is generally perceived as easygoing, friendly, relaxed and independent, with a deep desire for acceptance among peers. {1} is nonthreatening, sympathetic, hard to dislike and a good listener. {1} is likely to offer suggestions in indirect, offhanded ways. Abruptness is rare.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Others may see [Name] as disinterested or â&#128;&#156;on a missionâ&#128;&#157;. Those with soft personalities may see {2} as insensitive, self-centered and bullish. Detail-oriented people may perceive {2} as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. Others might also find {2} to be disorganized, inaccurate or someone who exaggerates facts.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.DisagreeingWith">Carefully document the position with facts and data that have been well researched, offering proof. Then ask [Name] to consider the case. Do not push too hard, but rather, provide {2} time to consider and process the evidence. {1} can be highly committed to new ideas, but postponing an immediate decision may cause {2} to lose {4} emotional attachment to the idea. Delaying the decision for even a day or two may open the door for {2} to accept other ideas.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.PossibleNegativePerceptionsOfOthers">POSSIBLE NEGATIVE PERCEPTIONS THIS PERSON HAS OF OTHERS</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.EnvironmentalStressors">Feeling cut off from social interaction and inadequate time for reflection. Can also feel stressed by othersâ&#128;&#153; disapproval.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] may quietly build resentment toward others who have a â&#128;&#156;bulldozerâ&#128;&#157; type of personality. {1} may see some people as being less motivated or trying to stall the process with trivial or excessive details. {1} may be jealous of someone else who receives more attention and may judge others as being too sensitive, pessimistic or slow in their work.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.MobilityPreference">Enjoys a flurry of activity that balances interacting with people, and adequate time for preparation and research.</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Instructor.description">Instructors have a desire to dramatically influence people as well as improve their surroundings. Whether through an assigned role or casual contact, they lead others by exerting an energetic personality. While leadership isn't always assigned, their ambition and goal-oriented vision makes them natural leaders. Instructors tend to focus on the big picture and are able to identify the motives of others while directing them toward a pre-determined goal. In a formal leadership role, Instructors may inspire or persuade others by using their verbal skills to recruit others to a cause. People are often attracted to their social skills and confidence.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.MotivationalStyle">Likes to set the pace.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] needs a manager who will tap into {4} creative flow and implement better ideas. {1} needs a leader who will help get things finished and begin new projects, one who is direct and who will accept {4} directness. A passive or carefree manager is not going to work. {1} may also need a manager who is strong enough to remind {2} to soften up, noting the impact {0} has on others.Â </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.RecommendedImprovements">Delegating responsibility can be difficult because [Name] prefers to do things {2}self to ensure the task is done correctly. Letting go is difficult too, as {0} has a tendency to over-manage. In fact, some may think of {2} as a micro-manager.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] may view those with strong personalities as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. {1} may also be concerned that others do not have the details to make good decisions. May see others as less motivated, disorganized and inaccurate, and become impatient with them.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.WhenPressured">Tends to internalize conflict, remembering previous slights.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.RecommendedImprovements">[Name] dislikes having to give direct orders and may be too lenient with unproductive work associates. In an effort to smooth things over, {0} may be hasty to resolve conflict with those who might be upset. There is also the possibility of holding grudges against those who are critical of {2}. {1} may be inclined to struggle with disorganization, overlooking key details and becoming easily distracted.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.SummaryOfStrengths">Independent, result-oriented, confident, problem-solver and direct.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.CommunicatingWith">Provide the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; before providing any explanations, details and concerns. Since PIONEERS are not good listeners by nature, compose thoughts into a short memo for [Name], detailing the problems, options and recommended actions. {1} is likely to be open to personal testimony and endorsement, especially from those who are well-connected. Persuade {2} by conveying who is involved and who thinks it is a good idea.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.SummaryOfStrengths">Accurate, tenacious, self-starting, capable of excellence, thrives on challenge.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Enjoys challenges, variety and the opportunity to influence and inspire others. May strive for prestige and recognition.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] has an entrepreneurial attitude and is assertive, persuasive, independent and adventurous. {1} can have a stubborn determination and is not afraid to try something new, seeking to move ahead even without the advice or backing of others. Boredom is {4} enemy, as {0} drives toward bigger and better things. Being flexible and self-motivated, {0} usually has a high tolerance for pressure.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.WhenPressured">May become increasingly disorganized or careless. May be overly sentimental.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.MobilityPreference">Able to remain still for long period of time, pondering the issues at hand.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.WhenPressured">May become belligerent when {4} individual approach is thwarted or the door to challenges is closed. May become a loner when things need to get done, which can diminish {4} reputation.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.summary4">[Name] is inclined to desire freedom to explore and re-check decisions, and may project an aloofness or bluntness that creates distance from work colleagues. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.summary3">Though {0} may not realize it, [Name] can sometimes prioritize the â&#128;&#156;missionâ&#128;&#157; over the personal relationships involved. As such, personal relationships may not receive the attention necessary to keep a team on the same page, especially when changes are implemented. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.summary2">[Name] can be both aggressive and sensitive at the same time in {4} quest to achieve {4} desired outcome. Decision making can be stalled by {4} desire to explore all possible options before arriving at a conclusive decision. With a strong task orientation, {0} is likely to implement sound changes and has the ability to plan considerably. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.MobilityPreference">Seeks an outlet for energy through variety, change and the quick attainment of goals.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.summary1">Individuals with a NAVIGATOR personality portrait tend to exhibit seemingly opposing strengths. As a NAVIGATOR, [Name] may not always be fully aware of how {4} strong personality is perceived by others. {1} desires tangible results and perfection.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is generally perceived as conscientious, logical, reserved, reflective and careful to avoid unnecessary risks. {1} may be very perceptive of hidden agendas or ulterior motives, and has difficulty relaxing until there is certainty of a decision or action being fundamentally sound.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.DrivingIdeal">Has a high ambition for personal growth and achievement.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.EnvironmentalStressors">Isolation or being confined to a desk. Tends to procrastinate then become stressed about deadlines.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.DrivingIdeal">Prefers to work in a predictable and controlled environment and maintain the status quo.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Ambassador">https://vimeo.com/175366495</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Detailed people may perceive [Name] as a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157;. Some may see {2} as disorganized, inaccurate or have a tendency to exaggerate the facts. Others can be worn down by {4} tendency to talk excessively at the expense of achieving results. Some people may be jealous of how much attention {0} receives from work associates and those within {4} social circle.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.WhenPressured">WHEN PRESSURED </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] prefers a democratic, relaxed management style and may not work well in a stressful, threatening environment. {1} works in an unhurried style and may need some friendly prodding to set and meet realistic deadlines. {1} prefers a manager who is personable and willing to show open appreciation for good work. {1} does not respond well to abrupt people and favors leadership with a â&#128;&#156;we''re in this together as a team" approach.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] has a basic desire to be unassuming, dependable and conscientious. There is an expectation that others will be considerate and fair in return. {1} generally respects others and seeks to please. However, in some situations, the desire to please can result in {2} becoming caustic and exhibiting an iron will when {0} feels taken advantage of. [Name] can be easily hurt by rejection or when overlooked and tends to hang on to that hurt. Seek to avoid contention, conflict and complications.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Others may see [Name] as being overly concerned with the details. On occasion, {0} may appear to be pessimistic, judgmental and picky. At times, others may find {2} to be rigid or inflexible.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.MobilityPreference">Likes to be active and continually seeks new challenges. Flourishes when there is variety in the workplace. Desires freedom from details and confining routines.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.CommunicatingWith">Since the INFLUENCER is naturally logical, organized and accurate, [Name] may resist change and be inflexible unless {0} first understands the reasons for change. Provide the rationale for change, decisions and actions by using well-researched details, facts and data. Clarify how the new idea may be fun and interesting. Persuade {2} by conveying who is involved and who thinks it is a good idea.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] is prone to be inherently patient, personable, unassuming and steadfast. {1} wants to work with and help people in a personal and unhurried environment. Regardless of {4} job description, [Name] will generally advise others in a good-natured and pleasant way.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.type">Adaptable/Precision</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] enjoys discovering new possibilities given the time to ponder, explore and probe. In fact, {0} often uncovers more alternatives than work associates can imagine.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.AssessesOthersBy">Their commitment to friendship, followed by competency.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.DrivingIdeal">Strives to manage, influence and inspire others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.MotivationalStyle">Developing and following proper procedures. Being an example to others when mastering new skills.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.EnvironmentalStressors">Routine tasks, lack of rapid progress or access to people.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.UneasyWhen">There is conflict and disharmony among co-workers, especially when forced to take sides.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.AssessesOthersBy">The use of information and data that is factual and accurate.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Easily grasps the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; and utilizes verbal skills and high energy to mobilize people and achieve results. Welcomes a challenge, especially the opportunity to create something new. Can have a â&#128;&#156;can doâ&#128;&#157; or â&#128;&#156;let''s show themâ&#128;&#157; attitude matched by an action-orientation.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.primary.summary">The SurePeople Primary Personality Portrait describes how we present ourselves to others, as well as how others perceive us, in non-stressful situations.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.Leadership">Defines the goal and then motivates others to work together to accomplish that goal.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Instructor">https://vimeo.com/175366560</entry><entry key="profile.video.Navigator">https://vimeo.com/175366569</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.WhenPressured">Can become restless, impatient and critical.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.summary5">[Name] may be perceived as direct, blunt, forceful or uncaring in some situations. While this drive for good results is a strength, when carried too far, it may create difficulty for others who are not as driven.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.summary4">Being objective and results-oriented, [Name] may prefer to work alone to achieve the best results, but {0} also has the ability to persuade others to join in to accomplish {4} desired result. [Name] can rise to the occasion and be a â&#128;&#156;take chargeâ&#128;&#157; individual when it is necessary. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.CommunicatingWith">{1} may be open to personal testimony and endorsement because {0} is motivated to relate to others, especially to those who are well-connected. Persuade {2} by conveying who is involved and who thinks it is a good idea. Also, show how the project will be fun or interesting. Paint the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157;, but remind [Name] of the details often or they may be forgotten. Because {0} is inclined to be practical, [Name] will want to know the specifics of how things will be done and how it will affect others. Prepare {2} in advance for change.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.RelationalTaskOrientation">Relates well with people, but prioritizes tasks under pressure.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.summary3">[Name] strives to remain free from situations considered constraining, such as those involving direct controls, routine work or excessive details. {1} needs independence and may become restless when outcomes are diminished by groupthink or committees. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.summary2">The PIONEER may project a self-confidence that can be misinterpreted by some as being arrogant or overly self-reliant. As such, [Name] generally seeks to take on opportunities that stretch and develop {4} abilities. If told that something cannot be done, {0} is likely to respond with a â&#128;&#156;can doâ&#128;&#157; attitude.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.RelationalTaskOrientation">Prioritizes achieving the goal and completing the task at hand. Relationships can become secondary to achieving the desired result.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.WhenPressured">May overstep boundaries and â&#128;&#156;bulldozeâ&#128;&#157; others, resisting being a team player while becoming overly critical of others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.summary1">Individuals with a PIONEER personality portrait possess several opposing strengths and are among the strongest of the personality types. That means [Name] generally doesnâ&#128;&#153;t have a problem assuming difficult challenges, strenuous tasks or competitive situations. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.JobMatch">The PEACEMAKER personality has an influential nature and may function most effectively when given the opportunity to influence, meet or entertain people. That means [Name] needs variety and opportunities to express new and creative ideas without a lot of detailed-oriented work. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be active, humorous, loyal and relational; communicate, entertain and follow the leader; gain recognition, influence, network and perform; set an example, support others and master familiar material.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.DisagreeingWith">Carefully document facts and data that have been well researched. Offer proof before asking [Name] to consider the case. Do not push too hard, and allow time to consider the evidence, apply logic and process the information. Do not put {2} on the spot by embarrassing or correcting {2}.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.MotivationalStyle">Strives to find innovative solutions to problems. Projects a personal sense of power and confidence.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.WhenPressured">Is flexible and adapts to the needs of work associates, accommodating the thinking of the team. However, if {4} convictions are bulldozed over, there may be a hidden iron will.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.SummaryOfStrengths">Verbal, persuasive, optimistic, loyal and cooperative.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.SummaryOfStrengths">Independent, results-oriented, confident, problem-solver and direct.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.RecommendedImprovements">While {0} can see the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157;, [Name] may not fully understand the amount of detailed work that is required. Seeking feedback from work associates and friends who are more detail-oriented would help [Name] gain a better understanding of the steps involved in a particular process. {1} can also struggle with disorganization and overlook key facts while distracted, so it would help to take time to plan, write down details and stay focused.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.RecommendedImprovements">[Name]â&#128;&#153;s impact on others is stronger than {0} may realize. With {4} strong personality, [Name] either empowers people or leaves them feeling hurt and criticized. At times, {0} may be too blunt and critical. When someone doesn''t measure up to {4} standards, [Name] can be prone to hurting their feelings. Learning to delegate, communicate softly and be patient would be helpful.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Usually accurate and efficient with the details and is not easily distracted. Likely work on the task with determination to follow through, either working with others or alone.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.underPressure.heading">PERSONALITY UNDER PRESSURE</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.CommunicatingWith">Since the ARCHITECT is naturally logical, organized and accurate, [Name] may resist change and be inflexible unless {0} first understands the reasons for change. Provide the rationale for change, decisions and actions by using well-researched details, facts and data. {1} usually prefers to have detailed instructions and an exact job description that lets {2} know what is expected. [Name] prefer to be included in decisions rather than making them independently of others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.AssessesOthersBy">Their positive attitude and recognition of the good in people.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.JobMatch">The INFLUENCER personality is generally motivated to be accurate, precise and practical. That means [Name] prefers work that is organized and structured with clear objectives and will need opportunities to entertain, meet and influence people. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be accurate, active, humorous and thorough; analyze, communicate, critique and improve; entertain, influence, interact, network, organize and perform; plan, process, reflect, relate, research and verbalize.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.type">Powerful/Adaptable</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.type">Versatile</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">There is a need for work variety that allows adequate time to prepare and interact with people.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.Over-uses">Praise and optimism. May be perceived by others as patronizing.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.DisagreeingWith">Carefully document facts and data that have been well researched. Offer proof before asking [Name] to consider the case. Do not push too hard, and allow time to consider the evidence, apply logic and process the information. Do not put {2} on the spot by embarrassing or correcting {2}.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.type">Powerful/Adaptable/Precision</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Visionary.description">Visionaries are strong individualists who continually strive to seek new objectives and agendas. They are independent, self-reliant, and often forward-thinking in their approach. Innovative solutions are often discovered because of their enterprising nature and internal belief that there must be a better way. Visionaries exhibit tenacity and intentionality when pursuing a goal while thriving on challenges and making important advancements. Since they're focused on results, they have the capacity for difficult endeavors that may be unsuitable for others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.AssessesOthersBy">The way they apply acceptance, inclusion and tolerance.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Prefers a harmonious and structured setting. Seeks the opportunity to encourage, develop and nurture people. Being spontaneous by nature, {0} prefer to be free from rigid deadlines or details.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Prefers working alone on projects without being bothered by small talk or interruptions. Also prefers written communications rather than conversation.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] has an entrepreneurial attitude and is assertive, persuasive, independent and adventurous. {1} can have a stubborn determination and is not afraid to try something new, seeking to move ahead even without the advice or backing of others. Boredom is {4} enemy, as {0} drives toward bigger and better things. Being flexible and self-motivated, {0} usually exhibits a high tolerance for pressure.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.CommunicatingWith">Provide the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; before providing any explanations, details and concerns. Since CATALYSTS are not good listeners by nature, compose thoughts into a short memo for [Name], detailing the problems, options and recommended actions. {1} will likely be open to personal testimony and endorsement, so persuade {2} with information about who is involved and who thinks it is a good idea. Also show how the project will be fun and interesting. Remind {2} of the details often or they may be forgotten.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">A manager or supervisor needs to use logic rather than an emotional approach with [Name]. Keep in mind {0} may prefer to work alone on projects and be given challenging problems along with adequate time to arrive at the best answer. {1} may also need a manager who is strong enough to remind {2} to soften {4} approach when dealing with others.Â </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.RecommendedImprovements">[Name] should strive to be more direct and purposeful in relationships as some find {4} casual and indirect style to be superficial. It would help to be more of a diplomat than a taskmaster in work relationships. {1} should work on following through, displaying sensitivity when disagreeing with others, and identifying the proper work pace. {1} should discover a means to find balance in personal tasks by listening to others'' ideas. As [Name] can be too sensitive in the work environment, {0} should try not to take things personally.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.SummaryOfStrengths">Dependable, loyal, cooperative and patient. Will focus on forgiveness and restoration.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Actuary">https://vimeo.com/175366653</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.WhenPressured">May be very tactful and diplomatic. However, may also become inflexible, perhaps even negative and caustic, if {4} personal convictions are disregarded.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.DisagreeingWith">First, find the larger goal that can be agreed upon, then propose the plan that will expedite the plan. {1} can be highly committed to reaching a goal, with the particular methodology a lesser priority. Pointing out small and insignificant shortcomings will erode the relationship over time. Be willing to discuss matters openly in a democratic manner, but avoid asking â&#128;&#156;whyâ&#128;&#157;. Instead, make inquiries by asking, â&#128;&#156;How did you arrive at your decision?â&#128;&#157; Or â&#128;&#156;Iâ&#128;&#153;m not sure if I understand, can you tell me more?â&#128;&#157; Taking this approach during conflict will minimize {4} defensiveness. Being respectfully direct and allowing frankness will go a long way. When making a request, let [Name] know what you want, then give {2} the latitude to accomplish the request in {4} own way.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] may quietly build resentment toward others who have a strong personality. {1} may view others as trying to bog down the process with trivial and excessive caution or details. {1} may also feel judged by others or may take it personally when someone else is in conflict with {2}.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.RelationalTaskOrientation">Has tendencies to be very task-driven and result-oriented. Likely to be detailed and specific rather than global in orientation. Interactions with others can be brief and direct.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.EmotionalPosture">Possesses a deep desire to appear good to professional associates and others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.RelationalTaskOrientation">Relates well with people, but prioritizes the task under pressure.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.EmotionalPosture">Individualistic when it comes to personal needs. Fear and timidity are uncommon emotions, though {0} can fear losing control.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.Leadership">Usually has a strong ability to lead with enthusiasm, mobilize the troops and influence by offering precise information.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.EnvironmentalStressors">Becomes anxious when there is unresolved conflict, anger and personal problems among co-workers. Uncomfortable when required to confront an issue.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.EmotionalPosture">A rugged individualist with the ego and strength to verbalize a personal perspective and position.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.CommunicatingWith">{1} is likely to be practical, accurate and organized but has a tendency to resist change. Work associates may want to approach {2} in a gentle and non-controversial manner, giving specifics of how things might need to change. Prepare {2} in advance as {0} likely doesnâ&#128;&#153;t appreciate surprises or abrupt changes. [Name] may be motivated by logic on some occasions and by feelings at other times. Attempt to understand the effects a change might have on {2} before pressing to implement those changes.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.JobMatch">The AMBASSADOR personality functions most effectively when given an opportunity to influence, meet or entertain people. That means [Name] needs variety and opportunities to express new and creative ideas without a lot of detail-oriented work. {1} cooperates well with others in order to complete a task or objective. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be active, humorous, loyal and relational; communicate, entertain, follow the leader, gain recognition, influence, master familial material; network, perform, set an example, support others and verbalize.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] responds best to a relaxed and amiable manager {0} considers a friend. Having a manager who shows appreciation and interest will motivate {2} toward greater productivity, while gentle prodding will help {2} get started. A manager who shows interest in {4} family life would be helpful. Allowing [Name] to specialize in a work area will increase the likelihood of {2} remaining in a particular job setting.Â </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.UneasyWhen">Itâ&#128;&#153;s necessary to be involved with large groups or to sell abstract ideas.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Seeks harmonious relationships, an even pace and considerate work associates.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.OrganizationalImpact">May potentially be a designer and initiator of change within an organization.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.EmotionalPosture">Usually willing to accept others with a friendly manner.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.MobilityPreference">MOBILITY PREFERENCE</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] prefers a democratic, relaxed management style and may not work well in a stressful, threatening environment. {1} prefers a manager who is personable and willing to show open appreciation for good work. {1} works in an unhurried style and may need some friendly prodding to set and meet realistic deadlines. {1} does not respond well to abrupt people and favors leadership with a â&#128;&#156;we''re in this together as a team" approach.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.DisagreeingWith">First, find the larger goal that can be agreed upon, then propose the plan that will expedite the plan. [Name] can be highly committed to reaching a goal, with the particular methodology a lesser priority.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.EmotionalPosture">Tends to reject interpersonal aggression. Can be critical and intolerant of careless workers.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.DisagreeingWith">First, find the larger goal that can be agreed upon, then propose the plan that will expedite the plan. {1} can be highly committed to reaching a goal, with the particular methodology a lesser priority. Postponing an immediate decision may cause {2} to lose {4} emotional attachment to the idea. Delays of even a day or two may open the door for {2} to accept other ideas.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Tough_N_Tender">https://vimeo.com/175366685</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is enthusiastic, talkative and diplomatic. If there is a need to influence others, {0} will likely do so with tact and modesty. {1} mixes well in social and business situations, making small talk easily and opening conversations with a smooth and low-pressure approach. {1} generally maintains a pleasant atmosphere of good will with an easygoing attitude and has a good sense of humor.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.Over-uses">Favors indirectness, excessive tolerance and kindness.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.UneasyWhen">There is a fixed environment that does not allow for variety. May experience a fear of losing the respect of work associates when relationships become strained due to conflict.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.MotivationalStyle">An ability to be persistent. Demonstrates a sheer force of personality.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Detailed people may find [Name] disorganized, inaccurate and likely to exaggerate. Others may be jealous of how much attention {0} receives from work associates or those within {4} social circle. People with strong personalities may see {2} as unassertive and less productive because of {4} tendency to make relationships a higher priority than completing the task.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHave">NEGATIVE PERCEPTIONS OTHERS MAY HAVE OF THIS PERSON</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.Leadership">Generally leads with good planning and organization. Uses procedures and structures to manage the work environment.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Examiner">https://vimeo.com/175366553</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Persistent and determined in reaching goals. Strong on follow-through and usually sets and completes important tasks with a determination that rivals that of nearly all others.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Supporter">https://vimeo.com/175366485</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.DisagreeingWith">Provide specific examples of how an idea, concept or plan has worked in other settings. Take a team approach and reassure [Name] of personal relationships since disagreement may be interpreted as a personal rejection. Assurances of being â&#128;&#156;in this togetherâ&#128;&#157; helps {2} relax and accommodate something new and different.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.NotableCharacteristics">Notable Characteristics</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.WhenPressured">May become argumentative and choose a passive-aggressive approach.</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Supporter.description">Allies are calm, modest and always willing to accommodate others. They lead others and relate in a supportive and personal manner. Allies maintain a low profile by blending into work and social situations. They're reliable and work at a steady and predictable pace while keeping the peace and mediating among contentious people. They influence others with their accommodating nature, pleasant posture and consistent work performance. Allies are likely to lead by being helpful to those in the workplace who are considered friends. They achieve remarkable consistency in work performance when there's the opportunity to specialize within a predictable environment. Expressed appreciation and affirmation from work associates go a long way in motivating them.</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Ambassador.description">Ambassadors naturally network well with others and have an ability to talk about anything with anyone. Ambassadors approach life with a people first philosophy. They are supportive and maintain relationships with diplomacy, personal warmth and understanding. They are likely to solve problems by listening, showing tolerance and offering suggestions. Ambassadors typically notice and encourage the strengths of others and maintain long-term relationships; likewise, they respond well to encouragement from others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] wants independence but needs to know there are limits to {4} personal authority. {1} needs to know why certain things are expected, as {0} works best with clear directions. This will allow for the highest level of performance. {1} may not respond well to close supervision, so avoid micromanaging. [Name] needs a manager who is willing to discuss matters openly in a democratic and lighthearted manner.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.summary4">[Name] may overestimate the ability of others. {1} might spend too much time talking and need help planning in order to manage details and organize the day-to-day. {1} may get lost in social relationships at the expense of the goal.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] can be aggressive, persuasive and action-oriented. {1} will strive for desired results regardless of the obstacles. Quitting or â&#128;&#156;giving inâ&#128;&#157; is unlikely as {0} thrives on challenging endeavors. When the environment seems favorable, [Name] can be very friendly, but if the environment is antagonistic, {0} can get very tough-minded.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.summary3">[Name] generally possesses an ability to promote ideas and inspire enthusiasm in others, and may be inclined to be more excited about a conference or meeting because of who is there. {1} is usually optimistic and can form favorable conclusions without having all the details nailed down. Antagonizing others intentionally is rare.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.summary2">[Name] is likely to lead with enthusiasm and desire a positive social environment where maintaining contact with people is necessary. This preference is so strong that {0} might opt for less interesting tasks if it means {0} has the chance to interact with people on a regular basis. Because of the broad network {0} has established, [Name] likely has access to people who can be very helpful in many different areas. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.summary1">Individuals with a CONNECTOR personality portrait are usually outgoing and socially adept. As a CONNECTOR, building friendships in a variety of settings comes naturally to [Name], as does maintaining an extensive network of contacts. {1} can be a people magnet with a natural ability to attract others to {4} cause. </entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Designer.description">Pioneers possess a variety of strengths and are naturally ambitious. They generally have no problem assuming difficult challenges, strenuous tasks or competitive situations. Pioneers are assertive, enterprising and project abundant self-confidence. They intentionally seek to take on opportunities that stretch and develop their abilities. If told that something cannot be done, Pioneers are likely to respond with a can do attitude. Being objective and results-oriented, they may prefer to work alone to achieve the best results, but they also have the ability to persuade others to join in to accomplish a desired result. Pioneers can rise to any occasion and become a take charge individual whenever necessary.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] may be perceived by others as conservative, reserved and conscientious, but is generally cooperative, precise, courteous and diplomatic. Following procedures and living up to high standards is considered very important to {2}. {1} tends to look ahead, thereby avoiding unnecessary trouble and risk. [Name] generally follows directions carefully and has a passion for accuracy and order.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.Leadership">Leads by being loyal and dependable.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.MobilityPreference">Staying in one place for an extended period is preferred in order to maintain focus. It is usually important to complete one task or project before starting another.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.Over-uses">Bluntness, directness and suspicion of others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.JobMatch">The STRATEGIST personality is a “take charge” kind of person, so [Name] is likely to be most effective when given independence, challenges, obstacles to overcome, problems to solve and a minimum of details. Because of {4} influential nature, {0} may also function best when given the opportunity to meet or entertain people. That means [Name] needs variety and opportunities to express new and creative ideas without a lot of detail-oriented work. In a job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be active, humorous and in control; build, communicate, create, decide, develop and direct; entertain, gain recognition, influence, initiate solutions and lead others; manage, network, perform, relate, solve problems, supervise and verbalize.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.Leadership">Tends to lead in the spotlight, selling the vision or product with high energy, excessive talk, humor and enthusiasm.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">People-oriented, enjoys variety, recognition and prestige, without a lot of detail-oriented work.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.Leadership">Leads by setting an example and achieving goals and objectives. {5} work ethic may encourage others to work harder. Possibly has an ability to deal directly with people in a calm manner.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] prefers a democratic, relaxed management style and may not work well in a stressful, threatening environment. {1} prefers a manager who is personable and willing to show open appreciation for good work. {1} works at an unhurried pace and may need some friendly prodding to set and meet realistic deadlines. [Name] does not respond well to abrupt people, but likes a leadership approach that says, "Weâ&#128;&#153;re in this together."</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.EnvironmentalStressors">When {0} is unable to exercise control over workplace direction, purpose and goals. Routines and excessive details can cause anxiety.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.CommunicatingWith">Provide {2} with the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; before providing any explanations, details and concerns. Since the STRATEGIST is not by nature a good listener, compose thoughts into a short memo for {2} that details the problems, options and recommended actions. [Name] will likely be open to personal testimony and endorsement, so persuade {2} with information about who is involved and who thinks it is a good idea. Also show how the project will be fun and interesting. Remind {2} of the details often or they may be forgotten.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.Leadership">Generally assumes authority as a leader, defining goals and delegating tasks without difficulty. May have a daring style with little or no fear in attempting something new or innovative. Holding others accountable for producing results come naturally.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.type">Powerful/Versatile</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] is a self-starter who responds immediately to competition in an effort to avoid unnecessary risks or trouble. {1} can be logical and critical, employing a personal approach to attain a goal. Problems are seen as a challenge, requiring unique and analytical efforts. At times, [Name] can be aggressive, systematic, factual and impatient. {1} may pick up little nuances and hidden meanings that are often missed by others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.DrivingIdeal">Has a strong desire for friends and to be content in relationships.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.RecommendedImprovements">Concealing grievances and holding grudges can be a problem if [Name] doesnâ&#128;&#153;t speak up. {1} may be prone to compromise too much in an attempt to keep the peace and may be hesitant to initiate change because of a desire to maintain the status quo. {1} would benefit by learning to be more flexible and expressing ideas more frequently. Feedback from others would help improve [Name]â&#128;&#153;s self-confidence.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.RelationalTaskOrientation">Primarily task-oriented, enjoys working alone.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.Over-uses">Unrealistic expectations of self and others. May place too much attention on personal objectives.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Navigator.description">Navigators can be both assertive and sensitive in their quest to achieve a desired outcome. Navigators desire tangible results and implement sound, procedural methods to attain them. They're likely to implement practical changes and have the ability to plan considerably. They are naturally cautious, which proves beneficial when exploring and analyzing decisions, and works well when given a certain measure of freedom to do so.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.JobMatch">The ARCHITECT personality seeks to be logical, accurate, practical and thorough, so [Name] functions most effectively when {4} work environment is structured and organized. {1} has an ability to follow through on projects and can be very loyal. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be accurate, considerate, free of conflict, loyal, relational, single-focused, still and thorough; analyze, critique and improve, experience familiarity, follow orders and procedures; organize, plan, process and research; support others, think and work with data and objects.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.EmotionalPosture">May be accommodating, nonthreatening, gentle, unassertive and moderate when approaching others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] can be a challenge to manage as {0} views suppression of emotions as virtuous and takes pride in being analytical, logical and thorough. A direct but sincere approach is the best course to take when managing {2}. Do not embarrass [Name] in public, since {0} already has a hard time living up to personal standards. Doing so most certainly will diminish the respect {0} holds for you. Frankness will go a long way, so let {2} know what is needed, then allow space to do the job {4} own way. It is very likely that the job will be done correctly.Â </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.SummaryOfStrengths">Verbal, persuasive, enthusiastic, analytical, cautious, organized and detailed.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.EffectivenessWouldIncrease">With more collaboration and cooperation, greater tact and personal warmth, and the recognition that limitations exist in {4} work role.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] can be incredibly productive with the right manager. {1} works best with a manager who is direct and straightforward, and with whom {0} can be direct. {1} wants to feel free to raise issues and negotiate on equal ground. Projects that may intimidate others can challenge [Name]. When told that something is impossible, [Name] is inclined to find a solution. A manager may have to remind {2} of just how potent {4} comments may be and make {2} aware of the impact words may have on work associates and subordinates.Â </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.type">Powerful</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.EnvironmentalStressors">People who talk too much, pry into private matters or display a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. The most significant sources of stress are people who block their path to success.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.MotivationalStyle">Tenacious attention to the details and accuracy.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.UneasyWhen">There is a loss of power or influence. Fears being too soft in certain situations.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.AssessesOthersBy">How they project personal strength and influence others, and their character.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.RelationalTaskOrientation">Tends to be both task-oriented and socially oriented. Interacting with people is very important, but so is the opportunity to prepare adequately.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] is driven and confident, with an ability to charge ahead despite the obstacles. {1} views resistance and opposition as challenges and is most effective when innovation and results are important.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.MobilityPreference">Desires a variety of projects. Seeks a constant flurry of activity and change.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.MobilityPreference">Overnight travel is probably not preferable. Prefers consistency, steadiness and regularity in the work environment. Routine is important.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.SummaryOfStrengths">Analytical, detailed, organized, cautious and accurate.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.SummaryOfStrengths">Verbal, persuasive, enthusiastic, independent, confident and versatile.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Pragmatist">https://vimeo.com/175366598</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Detailed people may find [Name] disorganized, inaccurate and likely to exaggerate. Others may be jealous of how much attention {0} receives from work associates or those within {4} social circle. People with strong personalities may see [Name] as unassertive and less productive because of {4} tendency to make relationships a higher priority than completing the task.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.UneasyWhen">There is too much change, disorganization or conflict.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.DrivingIdeal">DRIVING IDEAL</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.summary4">[Name] has a strong drive for achievement but can also be socially driven. However, finding a good balance between tasks and relationships may be difficult. If not careful, {0} may lean toward achieving the goal at the expense of the relationship. {1} should tread carefully and find ways to be more adaptable and available when approaching others. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.summary3">[Name] tends to get locked into doing things {4} own way. Delegating important responsibilities may be a struggle unless {0} is fairly confident that the job is going to be done right. There may be a tendency to take the job back if another person does not meet {4} personal standards. Therefore it is important to practice keeping lines of communication open among work associates in order to expand options that are likely to deliver better results. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.summary2">In a work position, [Name] may need to consider how to integrate {4} personal goals with the goals of the group. Being accountable to the team, while exploring ways to accomplish personal goals, is key to {4} effectiveness with team members. [Name] is likely to possess a strong internal drive for accomplishment, applying the necessary pressure to attain the desired results. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.summary1">Individuals with a TOUGH &amp; TENDER personality portrait exhibit a soft demeanor, but can be tough when needed. As a TOUGH &amp; TENDER, [Name] is often motivated by deeply felt convictions, objectives and goals. Adherence to these standards can often take precedence over the group or organization. {1} should realize {4} powerful personality can both build and destroy.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.Leadership">Utilizes a cautious nature to maintain quality and initiates change that may be important in reaching long-range goals. Can often see the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; and the necessary steps to achieve objectives.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.AssessesOthersBy">ASSESSES OTHERS BY</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.AssessesOthersBy">Their willingness to be innovative, commitment to getting things done and whether they meet {4} personal standards.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Motivator">https://vimeo.com/175366531</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.CommunicatingWith">Since the RESEARCHER is motivated by logic and not emotions, [Name] resists change unless {0} understands the reasons behind it. Provide well-researched details, facts and data to explain the required change.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.CommunicatingWith">Provide the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; before providing any explanations, details and concerns. [Name] will likely be open to personal testimony and endorsement, so persuade {2} with information about who is involved and who thinks it is a good idea. Also show how the project will be fun and interesting. Remind {2} of the details often or they may be forgotten.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Enjoys challenges, variety and the opportunity to influence and inspire others. May strive for prestige and recognition.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.SummaryOfStrengths">Independent, result-oriented, confident, problem-solver and direct.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.EnvironmentalStressors">The confinement of routines, processing detailed information and lacking access to people. Tends to over-commit.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.JobMatch">The CATALYST is a “take charge” kind of leader, so [Name] may function most effectively when given independence, challenges, obstacles and problems with a minimum of details. {1} may function best when given the opportunity to direct, meet or entertain people. {1} needs a variety of opportunities to express new or creative ideas without a lot of detail-oriented work. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be active, humorous and in charge; communicate, decide, develop, direct and entertain; gain recognition, influence, initiate solutions and lead others; manage, network, perform and relate; solve problems, supervise and verbalize.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Researcher">https://vimeo.com/175366613</entry><entry key="profile.personality.FundamentalDesiresDrive">FUNDAMENTAL DESIRES/DRIVE</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.type">Adaptable/Versatile</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.RecommendedImprovements">Being carefully aggressive, rather critical and possessing high standards, [Name] tends to drive for results single-mindedly. The impact this has on others is stronger than {0} may realize. {1} either empowers others with {4} strong personality or leaves them feeling hurt and criticized. There is tension between the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; and getting the details together that may leave {2} struggling with indecision.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.primary.type">{0}</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.JobMatch">The VISIONARY is a “take charge” kind of person, so [Name] may function most effectively when given independence, challenges, obstacles to overcome, problems to solve and minimal details. In the job description, {1} prefers the opportunity to: be in control, build, create, decide, develop and direct; initiate solutions, lead others, manage, solve problems and supervise.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.JobMatch">The INSTRUCTOR personality is a “take charge” kind of person, so [Name] is most effective when given independence, challenges, obstacles to overcome, problems to solve and a minimum of details. Because of {4} influential nature, {0} functions best when given the opportunity to meet or entertain people. [Name] will need a variety of opportunities to express new and creative ideas and a minimum of focused or detail-oriented work. In a job description position, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be active, humorous and in charge; build, communicate, create, decide and develop; direct, entertain, influence, initiate solutions and lead others; manage, network, perform, problem-solve and relate; supervise, verbalize and gain recognition.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.AssessesOthersBy">Their job position and level of self-discipline.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.DisagreeingWith">First, find the larger goal that can be agreed upon, then propose the plan that will expedite the plan. [Name] can be highly committed to reaching a goal, with the particular methodology a lesser priority. Postponing an immediate decision may cause {2} to lose {4} emotional attachment to the idea. Delays of even a day or two may open the door for {2} to accept other ideas.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.AssessesOthersBy">Precise and accurate performance standards.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Easily grasps the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; and utilizes verbal skills, applying high energy to mobilize people and achieve results. Generally welcomes a challenge, especially the opportunity to create something new. Has the ability to move and encourage others to action, while expecting results. Generally a good starter but a poor finisher.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.DrivingIdeal">Strives to manage, influence and inspire others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.WhenPressured">Has a tendency to internalize conflict and dwell on past conflicts. Can be their own worst enemy.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">{1} is prone to see others with a similar personality as territorial. Conflict may ensue over control. {1} can be turned off by too much talk and not enough results, and may see others as less motivated or holding up the process with trivial and excessive attention to details. {1} may be jealous of someone else receiving more attention and may see others as being too sensitive, pessimistic or slow in their work.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] places importance on accuracy, as well as being factual, careful and cooperative. {1} strives to do things the right way.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Refiner">https://vimeo.com/175366503</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.MotivationalStyle">Competing for recognition.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.ToDisagreeWithAsLeader">TO DISAGREE WITH THIS PERSON </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] may exhibit an outgoing and uninhibited social style. There is a strong desire to control events, manage people, be persuasive and be well liked by others. {1} may prefer to first deal with the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; before exploring the details and avoids specific components and routine that can get tiresome.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.RelationalTaskOrientation">A â&#128;&#156;people personâ&#128;&#157; who may lose focus on the task at hand while engrossed in preserving relationships and maintaining harmony.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.Over-uses">Can be tied up with correct procedures and â&#128;&#156;fail-safeâ&#128;&#157; controls. May be reluctant to change, and be over-dependent on people and processes that have been previously engaged.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.DisagreeingWith">Pointing out small and insignificant shortcomings will erode the relationship with [Name] over time. Be willing to discuss matters openly in a democratic manner, but avoid asking â&#128;&#156;whyâ&#128;&#157;. Instead, make inquiries by asking, â&#128;&#156;How did you arrive at your decision?â&#128;&#157; Or â&#128;&#156;Iâ&#128;&#153;m not sure if I understand, can you tell me more?â&#128;&#157; Taking this approach during conflict will minimize {4} defensiveness. Postponing an immediate decision may cause {2} to lose {4} emotional attachment to the idea. Delays of even a day or two may open the door for {2} to accept other ideas. Being respectfully direct and allowing frankness will go a long way. When making a request, let [Name] know what you want, then give {2} the latitude to accomplish the request in {4} own way.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.UneasyWhen">Losing in competitive interactions and when perceived poorly by others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.summary4">[Name] is likely to take offense at criticism but is motivated by recognition for a job well done. When in a position of responsibility, {0} excels in recognizing both the achievements of other group members and focusing on the quality of the work. {1} strives to build a pleasant and productive work environment.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.summary3">However, [Name] may also be a reserved communicator. Confronting the performance of others may not come naturally, and {0} may resort to indirect means when expressing expectations, making demands or disciplining others. {1} is likely to be overly tolerant of work associates who are unproductive. When managing others, {0} will sometimes put people above purpose to the extent that accomplishing the tasks may become a second priority. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.summary2">[Name] typically notices the strengths in others and maintains long-term relationships, going to great lengths to avoid making waves. {1} leaves a positive impression with {4} warmth, empathy and consideration, and {0} is likely to solve problems by listening and offering suggestions in a diplomatic, non-intrusive manner. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.DisagreeingWith">Appeal to both logic and a sense of â&#128;&#156;team-nessâ&#128;&#157; by reassuring {2} that the relationship is important. Focus on what is practical and how it has worked in the past. Offer proof before asking {2} to consider the case. Do not push too hard, and allow time to consider the evidence, apply logic and process the information. Remember that {0} places a high value on relationships.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.summary1">Individuals with a PEACEMAKER personality portrait relate exceptionally well to others and are strong networkers. As a PEACEMAKER, [Name]â&#128;&#153;s primary approach to life is one based on relationships rather than tasks or objectives. </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] is most likely to be offended by public embarrassment. Others who criticize or correct {2} publicly are sure to lose {4} respect. {1} may see others as disorganized, less prepared, less accurate and unproductive. There may be a tendency to be impatient with those less organized people and may see those with strong personalities as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. {1} may also be concerned with others not having the correct information to make good decisions.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.Leadership">Builds lasting friendships with people through mediating, caring and exhibiting genuine concern.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.JobMatch">[Name] is likely to work at an even pace and demonstrate an ability to follow through on projects. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be considerate, be free of conflict, be relational and single-focused and still; experience familiarity, follow directions and support others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers">[Name] may quietly build resentment toward others who have a strong personality. {1} may view others as trying to bog down the process with trivial and excessive caution or details. {1} may also feel judged by others or may take it personally when someone else is in conflict with {2}.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.MotivationalStyle">Likely to exhibit compassion, an â&#128;&#156;open doorâ&#128;&#157; philosophy and a willingness to listen. Desires to help others succeed in personal and corporate roles.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.DisagreeingWith">First, find the larger goal that can be agreed upon, then propose the plan that will expedite the plan. [Name] can be highly committed to reaching a goal, with the particular methodology a lesser priority. Postponing an immediate decision may cause {2} to lose {4} emotional attachment to the idea. Delays of even a day or two may open the door for {2} to accept other ideas.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">[Name] responds best to a manager who is available to interact on significant details and make useful suggestions. Although {0} functions well behind the scenes, {0} still desires to be appreciated for {4} contribution.Â </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.EmotionalPosture">Typically self-disciplined, determined and dispassionate.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.RecommendedImprovements">[Name]â&#128;&#153;s bluntness toward some people may be a problem. There may be a tendency toward perfectionism that keeps {2} from being completely satisfied with anything. This can give the appearance of being indecisive. It is suggested that [Name] learn to be more flexible, tolerant of others who are different, and personally involved with others. {1} may need to learn to relax more and maintain a healthy balance between private life and work.Â </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.Over-uses">Modesty and passivity. Can be resistant or reluctant to change.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Others may view {2} as disinterested or â&#128;&#156;on a missionâ&#128;&#157;. Those with soft personalities may view {2} as insensitive, self-centered and bullish. Detail-oriented people may perceive {2} as having a â&#128;&#156;know-it-allâ&#128;&#157; attitude. Others might also find {2} to be disorganized, inaccurate or one who exaggerates facts.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.AssessesOthersBy">The concrete results they accomplish.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.EnvironmentalStressors">Conflict, abrupt and unexpected changes, and a lack of consideration, appreciation or predictability.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.CommunicatingWith">{1} may be open to personal testimony and endorsement because {0} is motivated to relate to others. Persuade {2} by conveying who is involved and who thinks it is a good idea. Also, show how the project will be fun or interesting. Paint the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157;, but remind {2} of the details often or they may be forgotten. Because [Name] is inclined to be practical, {0} will want to know the specifics of how things will be done and how it will affect others. Prepare {2} in advance for change.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">HOW TO SUPERVISE AND ENCOURAGE</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Easily grasps the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; and utilizes verbal skills and high energy to mobilize people and achieve results. Generally welcomes a challenge, especially the opportunity to create something new. Has the ability to move and encourage others to action, while expecting results. Generally a good starter but a poor finisher.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] prefers to follow orders, rules and regulations and is suited for jobs that require meticulous work with high attention to detail. Being accurate and conservative, {0} can be an exceptional planner if {0} has the proper skills.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.JobMatch">The PRAGMATIST personality seeks to be logical, accurate, practical and thorough, so [Name] functions most effectively when {4} work environment is structured and organized. {1} needs a variety of opportunities to entertain, meet and influence people, as well as express creative ideas. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: be accurate, active, humorous and thorough; analyze, communicate, critique, improve and entertain; influence, interact, network, organize, perform and plan; process, reflect, relate, research, think and verbalize.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.EnvironmentalStressors">Inconvenient interruptions and office politics. Even prefers to avoid the spotlight and becomes stressed when credit is not given for a job well done. May be especially aware of work associates who fail to pull their fair share of the load.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.UneasyWhen">Others are antagonistic or resentful, or when {0} is perceived as incompetent. This often involves having {4} work evaluated, corrected or changed.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.FundamentalDesiresDrive">[Name] is patient, personable, unassuming and steadfast. Regardless of the situation, {0} will generally advise others in a good-natured and pleasant way.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.RecommendedImprovements">[Name] may want to develop ways to demonstrate appreciation for others who do things well, even though their method is not what {0} sees as the &amp;#157;&amp;rdquo;right way&amp;rdquo;. {1} may be prone to dawdle, hesitate and deliberate before taking a risk or making an important decision. It is suggested that {0} learns to act quicker and focus on compromising for a good, rather than perfect, solution.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.EnvironmentalStressors">Feels stress when there is unresolved conflict, excessive pressure to take charge of others or a deadline that would compromise relationships.</entry><entry key="profile.video.Promoter">https://vimeo.com/175366541</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.summary5">Because the SCIENTIST seeks accuracy and logic, [Name] may suffer from â&#128;&#156;paralysis of analysisâ&#128;&#157; and get caught in a cycle of worry. {1} should work to achieve a more flexible attitude.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.summary4">Since the SCIENTIST prefers a peaceful work environment, [Name] can be uncomfortable or reserved around more aggressive work associates. On the other hand, {0} can indirectly control the work environment by expecting or requiring others to stick with their rules. For [Name] this comes from a well-intentioned desire to be conscientious, but it may come across as critical or picky to others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.summary3">[Name] has a very strong task orientation. However, when in â&#128;&#156;task modeâ&#128;&#157;, {0} may neglect personal relationships, which can prove challenging for work associates. In fact, it may seem that [Name] operates by a secret rule book, which {0} expects others to follow. This can pose problems when work associates are unaware or unfamiliar with these unspoken rules.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.type">Powerful/Versatile/Adaptable</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.summary2">[Name] possesses a natural desire to think critically and act based on correctness, accuracy and well-researched facts. This approach has a strong impact on {4} decision-making process, as {0} will explore all possible options before arriving at a conclusive decision. If there is room for doubt, [Name] can go to great lengths to avoid being unprepared.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.summary1">Individuals with a SCIENTIST personality portrait are exceptionally detail-oriented and analytical. As a SCIENTIST, [Name] may feel a strong need to get things â&#128;&#156;just rightâ&#128;&#157; â&#128;&#147; a quality that others could see as inflexible.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Others may view [Name] as critical, judgmental and overly concerned with small details. Conflict can ensue over who is in control and correct. At times, some may perceive {2} as rigid and inflexible. It is possible that some will see {2} as a perfectionist.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.MobilityPreference">Enjoys a flurry of activity that includes interacting with people interspersed with down time that allows for adequate preparation and research.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.NegativePerceptionsMayHaveOfOthers.heading">Negative Perceptions [Name] May Have Of Others</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Prefers a work environment that allows for independence and creative thinking. Prefers defined goals and procedures.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.SummaryOfStrengths">SUMMARY OF STRENGTHS </entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.UneasyWhen">There is a loss of social acceptance or self-worth or when losing face among work associates.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.Over-uses">A win-lose competitive style. May become impatient when the pace of a project seems to move too slowly.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Navigator.MobilityPreference">Prefers a mix of being mobile and stationary.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Instructor.AssessesOthersBy">How they project a sense of personal strength, influence and character.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.UneasyWhen">Dealing with others who have lower standards that can impact the quality of {4} work.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.EmotionalPosture">Approachable, caring, affectionate and understanding.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.WorkEnvironmentContribution">May seem to know everyone and networks easily, even if {0} has difficulty remembering names. Influences people through friendship, enthusiasm, humor and strong communication skills. Good at promoting, relieving tension and creating positive relationships.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Refiner.DrivingIdeal">Strives for accomplishments that are predictable, measurable and productive. Works to high standards and strives to develop them.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.MotivationalStyle">Uses a friendly manner, openness and verbal adeptness. Can talk with anyone about anything.</entry><entry key="profile.spectrum.Examiner.description">Influencers are critical thinkers who utilize effective verbal skills to inspire others to a cause. They possess an effervescent personality and a good sense of humor. Influencers are likely to have a natural interest in detailed strategies that will accomplish an established goal. They can communicate the desired big picture and help others visualize the necessary steps needed to accomplish the goal. As such, they can be incredibly persuasive when engaging others in a task or project. Influencers are ambitious and precisely detailed in their approach while also considerate in their relationships.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.UneasyWhen">Life is boring, tasks become routine and there is a loss of control.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf.heading">Negative Perceptions Others May Have Of [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Encourager.RecommendedImprovements">[Name] dislikes having to give direct orders and may be too lenient with unproductive co-workers. In an effort to smooth things over, {0} may be hasty to resolve conflict with those who might be upset. There is also the possibility of holding grudges against those who are critical of {2}.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.MobilityPreference">Usually needs activity, change and variety. May become bored if given a narrow scope of responsibility.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.Leadership">Usually has a strong ability to lead enthusiastically, mobilizing the troops while influencing with precise information.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Prefers to work in a structured environment with clearly defined goals. Needs to have the freedom and authority necessary to accomplish those goals. Predictability and regularity are also desired.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.NegativePerceptionsOthersMayHaveOf">Others may see [Name] as being a perfectionist, indecisive or overly concerned with small details. {6} attention to detail may seem to be pessimistic when it comes to accepting new ideas. Because {0} prefers to be accurate and precise, those with soft personalities may feel judged.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Uses strong communication skills and personal enthusiasm to convince or motivate people toward a goal. A confident, natural promoter and seller, can close a deal, delegate responsibility and inspire others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.RelationalTaskOrientation">Tends to be both task- and relationship-oriented. Interacting with people is very important but so is the opportunity to prepare adequately.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.EnvironmentalStressors">Making changes without understanding why, not being included in the decision-making process, or being pressured to act without having adequate preparation time.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.HowToSuperviseAndEncourage">Being ambitious, [Name] may not be easy to manage. Give {2} freedom to run things the way {0} deems appropriate, but remind {2} that limitations to authority exist. {1} works best with a friendly supervisor with whom open discussion and honesty are expected and accepted.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.RecommendedImprovements">[Name] may be stubborn at times and refuse to change {4} position to the point of being blunt or obstinate in certain situations. As {0} may initially be skeptical, suggest focusing on being more open to othersâ&#128;&#153; perspectives. This will go a long way in improving {4} relationships. Since [Name] can see the â&#128;&#156;big pictureâ&#128;&#157; but may not fully understand the amount of work required, seeking feedback from work associates who are more detail-oriented would help.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.JobMatch">The RESEARCHER personality seeks to be logical and thorough, so [Name] functions most effectively when {4} work environment is structured and organized. In the job description, {0} prefers the opportunity to: analyze, be accurate, be in control, build and create; critique and improve, decide, develop, direct and initiate solutions; manage, organize, plan, quality control and research facts; solve problems, supervise, think things through and work with data and objects.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.type">Precision</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Ambassador.EmotionalPosture">Approachable, empathetic and compassionate. Caring and affectionate. Rejects aggression.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.Leadership">Defines the goal and then motivates others to work together to accomplish that goal.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Designer.MobilityPreference">Needs mobility. Prefers a variety of projects. Seeks a constant flurry of activity and change.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.CommunicatingWith.heading">Communicating With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Supporter.MotivationalStyle">Strives to be pleasing, accommodating and consistent in personal work performance.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Motivator.Over-uses">Enthusiasm, overselling and optimism.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.DisagreeingWith.heading">Disagreeing With [Name]</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Pragmatist.NotableCharacteristics">[Name] can be modest, sociable, predictable and cooperative. {1} can be careful and conservative, and minimize risks through careful investigation. {1} prefers an atmosphere that is harmonious and free from antagonism. {1} will most likely seek work-related projects where there is the opportunity to specialize. [Name] can create and maintain an atmosphere of goodwill if it is the primary objective.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Actuary.WorkEnvironmentContribution">Tends to be very conscientious about work, striving to be accurate, factual, analytical and thorough. Defines, clarifies, evaluates and obtains detailed information and researches information.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.MostFavorableWorkEnvironment">Functions most effectively when given the opportunity to overcome obstacles and solve problems independently.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Examiner.type">Versatile/Precision</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Tough_N_Tender.DisagreeingWith">First, find the larger goal that can be agreed upon, then propose the plan that will expedite the plan. {1} can be highly committed to reaching a goal, with the particular methodology a lesser priority. Be specific about how the new idea has worked in other settings. Offering reassurance that â&#128;&#156;we are in this togetherâ&#128;&#157; helps to ease into the change. Taking a team approach is the most effective path toward resolution.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Visionary.Over-uses">May be too controlling of circumstances or people.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Researcher.MotivationalStyle">Tenacity, determination and the ability to follow through.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Promoter.MotivationalStyle">Praise, opportunities, patronizing and doing favors for others.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.Innovator.EmotionalPosture">Does not back down easily and is not intimidated by aggression. Tends to minimize personal need for affirmation.</entry><entry key="profile.personality.MotivationalStyle">MOTIVATIONAL STYLE</entry><entry key="profile.personality.ToCommunicateWithAsLeader">TO COMMUNICATE WITH THIS PERSON</entry></properties>